<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ns0:feed xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><ns0:title>Cyprien in Peru</ns0:title><ns0:link href="https://cyprieninperu.netlify.app/" rel="alternate" /><ns0:link href="https://cyprieninperu.netlify.app/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self" /><ns0:id>https://cyprieninperu.netlify.app/</ns0:id><ns0:updated>2025-10-27T09:00:00-05:00</ns0:updated><ns0:entry><ns0:title>Finally?!</ns0:title><ns0:link href="https://cyprieninperu.netlify.app/going-abroad/?utm_source=atomfeed" rel="alternate" /><ns0:published>2025-10-27T09:00:00-05:00</ns0:published><ns0:updated>2025-10-27T09:00:00-05:00</ns0:updated><ns0:author><ns0:name>Cyprien Chevallier</ns0:name></ns0:author><ns0:id>tag:cyprieninperu.netlify.app,2025-10-27:/going-abroad/</ns0:id><ns0:summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I finally got around to publishing my first real article. I describe my first day in Peru, up until my journey towards my new home, Miguel&amp;nbsp;Grau.&lt;/p&gt;</ns0:summary><ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Although I’ve been in Peru for more than three weeks—well, almost two months—I hadn’t posted anything yet… until today! So let me tell you about those first few days in Lima, which served as preparation for my placement in Miguel&amp;nbsp;Grau.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything began on Friday, August 22. That day, the other volunteers and I boarded our flight to Lima, with a layover in Bogotá. Exhausted, a bit out of sorts, and loaded down with my three pieces of luggage, we finally arrived at our hostel at 3 a.m. The Flying Dog immediately gave me a taste of what I had signed up for. Our room, for example, looked out onto an aloe vera plant hanging on a brick wall. We also got along pretty easily with our neighbors (luckily, they were volunteers too), because the wall didn’t reach the ceiling and one window stayed permanently open. A bit farther down the hallway, I discovered Peruvian bathrooms for the first time: toilet paper strictly forbidden, unless you want to clog the pipes! The bathroom, home to a few spiders and insects acting as “pets,” at least had hot water… Looking back, none of this was actually so bad—you just have to&amp;nbsp;adapt!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Saturday, August 23,&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few hours of sleep, we started the day with a light breakfast and a meeting with Doris, our local Ecoselva mentor who will accompany us throughout the&amp;nbsp;year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon, we explored Miraflores, one of Lima’s wealthiest and most touristy districts—which also happened to be where our hostel was—and we visited the Pacific Ocean, where I unfortunately soaked the first of the four pairs of pants I had&amp;nbsp;brought…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also checked out the area around the hostel: a really nice bar with excellent Pisco Sours, big green parks filled with stray cats to pet or adopt, and a multi-day coffee market with tons of fascinating stands. Meals were taken care of by Ecoselva: lunch at an Arab restaurant, dinner at a Chinese one. The latter didn’t win many hearts— not only was the food pretty mediocre, but out of misguided curiosity, I ordered an aloe-vera drink. Imagine buying aloe-vera shampoo at the grocery store, then mixing in chunks of fruit yogurt—that’s exactly what it tasted like for me and 90% of the volunteers. But I shouldn’t complain: if our year were made only of perfect experiences, we’d be bored stiff—and I wouldn’t have absurd stories to tell. Like the scooter that suddenly drove into the restaurant during&amp;nbsp;dinner…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of the Pacific in Lima" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230536_DxO_HipNVxR4H.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of a metal pole with a sticker and the Pacific in the background" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230540_DxO_x4EQ_uVjc.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of a road and some buildings in Lima" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230556_DxO_Ldnar9w-0I.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="The Pacific behind a beton bridge" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230559_DxO_uBmd7MWe1.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Waves of the Pacific hitting Stones" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230600_DxO_eGgQayloN.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Sunday, August 24,&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Away from police patrols and cleaning crews, we discovered a very different side of the city. Lima, a metropolis of 11 million people, is marked by stark contrasts between wealth and poverty. We visited Villa María del Triunfo, a pueblo joven—a low-income neighborhood mainly inhabited by migrants from the Andes. The ride there was quite an experience: traffic laws are more like suggestions, seatbelts are optional accessories, and drivers use the horn more often than the&amp;nbsp;brakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once there, we were introduced to an urban-agriculture project. About fifteen years ago, a group of women decided to beautify the local landscape. Since construction is prohibited under electrical pylons, they secured permission to grow fruits and vegetables there. The beginning was tough—few people believed in the project. To protect the crops from thieves, the women built a makeshift fence out of tires, planks, and corrugated metal&amp;nbsp;sheets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, the project has expanded to other districts and now includes many families cultivating small plots. Some sell their produce, others grow food for their own use. All the gardens are arranged with a lot of love. At noon, we were invited to another garden in the project to enjoy a meal prepared with their fresh vegetables—absolutely delicious! Then we headed back to the hostel through Lima’s chaotic&amp;nbsp;traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent the rest of the day at the last session of Semana del Café, hidden among clouds of warm coffee aromas and the lively crowds. I met some interesting people, including a tattoo artist drawing temporary coffee-themed tattoos. Theo and I chatted with him about his life and work in Peru—giving him a much-needed break. Later, I exchanged contacts with several vendors from whom I bought sweaters, a fanny pack, and a new pair of pants. Because I have to admit: I packed terribly. Despite making a careful list and preparing everything meticulously, I forgot the most essential thing—myself. I left behind clothes, games, and other important and useful things in Germany. And what I did bring—like pants and t-shirts—isn’t nearly enough. As my best friend would say: “Life is hard.” I can’t change it now, so I’ve accepted it and&amp;nbsp;adapted!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Tríunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240631_DxO_xJ4J3gVrZ.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of a banana Tree" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240629_DxO_tmrYuPpMN.jpg"&gt;&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Zum ersten mal gesehen: Ein&amp;nbsp;Bananenbaum&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Tríunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240636_DxO_pZkmJkSXxO.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Tríunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240638_DxO_gi_7-5bmx.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Tríunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240642_DxO_xBG7qJlfa.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Monday, August 25,&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were supposed to meet with a woman from the German embassy to get information about the country and our volunteer &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ID&lt;/span&gt; card. In Peru, you often need a number called the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CNI&lt;/span&gt; (código único de identificación), which appears on the card. It’s essential for using Yape (a digital payment service, similar to PayPal, accepted almost everywhere), but also for hostels and big purchases. Unfortunately, the meeting didn’t happen because she was sick. Honestly, that worked out well—we finally had time to buy &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SIM&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We took the bus to Lima’s historic center. Anyone who complains about the crowded public transportation in Germany wouldn’t even be able to step inside a Lima bus. They were so packed that we had to twist ourselves more than in a game of Twister. Getting off was just as entertaining: you simply shout “¡Bajo!” and&amp;nbsp;“¡Pásame!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to the historic center: the impressive buildings date back to the Spanish colonial period, which began in 1535. When Lima was founded as the “City of Kings,” it became the seat of the Viceroyalty of Peru—one of the most important political and economic hubs of the Spanish Empire in South America. Wealthy settlers, the Church, and the colonial administration invested heavily in lavish churches, grand palaces, and well-preserved houses to display their power and wealth. Local materials such as brick, wood, and stone were crafted with great skill. We saw all of this during our visit to this &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UNESCO&lt;/span&gt; World Heritage Site. The historic center felt like a step back in time, with the beautifully preserved Plaza Mayor and our tour of the San Francisco monastery. While wandering through the streets, I also noticed how the urban landscape shifted: between the skyscrapers and modern buildings, a few historic structures remained—often now used by government&amp;nbsp;offices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ended the evening at the Parque de la Reserva, watching a water show while snacking on&amp;nbsp;churros.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250008_DxO_eZP13gl30.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250032_DxO_2TchPjv8a.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250045_DxO_mWZb9FTXF.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250052_DxO_1FiPlr7_e.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250099_DxO_y5kqsrqkm.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250124_DxO_6nd8-JWpU.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250154_DxO_XMbq0_BOW.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250172_DxO_qOFtIZhz_.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250213_DxO_Pl9ZYhu-a.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260224_DxO_clMn0PQo6.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260245_DxO_vUifIVnN9.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Tuesday, August 26,&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After another meeting with Doris, we headed to the tourist district of Barranco. We strolled along the seaside promenade and enjoyed the Pacific—where only a handful of brave souls (including me) dared to swim. Because it was so cold, the swimmers took a taxi back to the hostel. After some fresh empanadas, Jannes, Theo, and I ended the night with a Pizza Hut&amp;nbsp;dinner!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="A view of the Pacific" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260493_DxO_oWrPud-bS.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="A view of the Pacific with Limas skyscrapers and a Peruvian Flag" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260495_DxO_8yFdvy_U4.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cactuses with the Pacific in the Background" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260499_DxO_P4ImBAGCG7.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="A Closeup of a cactuses fruit" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260501_DxO_SkkT5tW59.jpg"&gt;&lt;p class="caption"&gt;The fruit found on the cactuses from the previous&amp;nbsp;photo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="A street in Lima leading to the Pacific in the background" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260504_DxO_GP6JGc0Tz.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="A pigeon flying over the waves of the pacific" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260510_DxO_3mTrgnlvv.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="A seagull flying over the pacific with the cityscape of Lima in the background" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260517_DxO_k_0ZP86hL.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Wednesday, August 27,&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we were all leaving Lima at different times and Doris wanted to be around, nothing official was planned for our last day. Erik and I had an afternoon meeting with David, the director of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CACI&lt;/span&gt; Satinaki, where we’ll work and live for the year. He explained a lot: who we’d be living and working with, details about traveling in the region, and&amp;nbsp;more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That evening, we left. In Peru, people often travel long-distance by bus, and the comfort level is far better than in Germany. There are large terminals for the different companies, complete with luggage check-in, and the buses are fantastic: wide, comfortable seats that recline 160 or even 180 degrees. So the ride to Pichanaki was looking pretty good! What happened 11 hours later will be the subject of the next&amp;nbsp;article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay&amp;nbsp;tuned,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buena semana y hasta la&amp;nbsp;próxima!&lt;/p&gt;</ns0:content><ns0:category term="peru" /></ns0:entry><ns0:entry><ns0:title>Es geht los!</ns0:title><ns0:link href="https://cyprieninperu.netlify.app/de/going-abroad/?utm_source=atomfeed" rel="alternate" /><ns0:published>2025-10-27T09:00:00-05:00</ns0:published><ns0:updated>2025-10-27T09:00:00-05:00</ns0:updated><ns0:author><ns0:name>Cyprien Chevallier</ns0:name></ns0:author><ns0:id>tag:cyprieninperu.netlify.app,2025-10-27:/de/going-abroad/</ns0:id><ns0:summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Endlich habe ich es geschafft, meinen ersten richtigen Artikel zu veröffentlichen. Ich beschreibe meinen ersten Tag in Peru bis hin zu meiner Reise in meine neue Heimat Miguel&amp;nbsp;Grau.&lt;/p&gt;</ns0:summary><ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Obwohl ich nun schon seit mehr als drei Woch- 2 Monaten in Peru bin, habe ich es bislang nicht geschafft, auch nur einen einzigen Artikel zu veröffentlichen – bis jetzt! Heute möchte ich von den wenigen Tagen in Lima berichten, die als Vorbereitung für meinen Einsatz in Miguel Grau&amp;nbsp;dienten.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alles begann am Freitag, dem 22. August. An diesem Tag stieg ich mit den anderen Freiwilligen in den Flieger nach Lima, mit kurzem Zwischenstopp in Bogotá. Mit viel Müdigkeit, Reisekrankheit und meinem dreiteiligen Gepäck kamen wir um 3 Uhr morgens in unserem Hostel an. Das Hostel &amp;#8220;Flying Dog&amp;#8221; ließ mich beim ersten Blick sofort realisieren, auf was ich mich eingelassen hatte. Unter anderem hatte unser Zimmer ein Fenster mit Blick auf eine Aloe-Vera-Pflanze, die an einer Backsteinmauer hing. Zu unseren Zimmernachbarn (zum Glück auch andere Freiwillige) hatten wir leichten Kontakt, da die Wand nicht bis zur Decke reichte und ein offenes Fenster eingelassen war. Ein Gang weiter entdeckte ich zum ersten Mal peruanische Toiletten: Achtung! Klopapier verboten, denn sonst verstopfen sich die Abwasserleitungen. Das Bad, das einige Spinnen und Insekten als „Haustiere“ beherbergte, hatte zum Glück noch warmes Wasser&amp;#8230; Im Nachhinein war alles halb so schlimm – man muss sich nur ein wenig&amp;nbsp;anpassen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Samstag, 23. August&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nach wenigen Stunden Schlaf ging es direkt weiter mit unserem Tagesprogramm: Nach einem eher kleinen Frühstück hatten wir ein Treffen mit Doris, unserer Landesmentorin von Ecoselva, die uns das ganze Jahr über betreuen&amp;nbsp;wird.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Im Laufe des Nachmittags entdeckten wir Miraflores, eines der wohlhabenderen Viertel Limas, das auf Touristen ausgelegt war und in dem unser Hostel lag, sowie den Pazifik, in dem ich leider meine erste von vier Hosen mit Salzwasser&amp;nbsp;tränkte&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wir erkundeten auch die Umgebung des Hostels: Eine sehr nette Bar mit gutem Pisco Sour, mehrere große Grünanlagen mit freilaufenden Katzen, die man streicheln und adoptieren konnte, sowie ein mehrtägiger Kaffeemarkt mit tollen Verkaufsständen aller Art. Für die Verpflegung war Ecoselva zuständig. So aßen wir mittags in einem arabischen Restaurant und abends in einem chinesischen. Letzteres überzeugte die wenigsten, da es zum einen zu viel schlechtes Essen gab und zum anderen wir, aufgrund eines Neugierimpulses meinerseits, ein Aloe-Vera-Getränk bestellten: Stell dir vor, du kaufst dir Shampoo mit Aloe-Vera-Duft im Supermarkt und packst darin kleine Stücke aus Fruchtjoghurt hinein. Genau so schmeckte es für mich und 90 % der Freiwilligen :( Hier möchte ich mich aber nicht beschweren, denn würde unser Jahr nur aus guten Erfahrungen bestehen, würden wir uns mächtig langweilen – und hier hätte ich keine absurden Erlebnisse zu teilen. Die Unterbrechung des Abendessens durch ein Moped, das in das Restaurant hineinfährt, gehört zu einem dieser absurden&amp;nbsp;Ereignisse&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of the Pacific in Lima" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230536_DxO_HipNVxR4H.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of a metal pole with a sticker and the Pacific in the background" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230540_DxO_x4EQ_uVjc.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of a road and some buildings in Lima" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230556_DxO_Ldnar9w-0I.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="The Pacific behind a beton bridge" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230559_DxO_uBmd7MWe1.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Waves of the Pacific hitting Stones" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230600_DxO_eGgQayloN.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Sonntag, 24. August&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weit entfernt vom wachenden Auge der Sicherheitskräfte und den säubernden Besen und Pinseln der Putzkräfte entdeckten wir heute eine neue Facette der Stadt. Lima: Eine Stadt mit 11 Millionen Einwohnern, die geprägt ist vom Kontrast zwischen Arm und Reich. Wir fuhren in das Viertel „Villa María del Triunfo“, ein sogenanntes pueblo joven – ein Armenviertel, das vor allem von Migranten aus den Anden bewohnt wird. Unser Weg dorthin war holprig, denn die StVO in Peru ist eher eine Empfehlung, der Gurt Dekoration und die Hupe wird mehr genutzt als die&amp;nbsp;Bremse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dort wurde uns ein Projekt der urbanen Agrikultur vorgestellt – vor ungefähr 15 Jahren entschieden sich einige Frauen, die Landschaft in der Umgebung schöner zu gestalten. Nachdem unter Strommasten ein Bauverbot herrscht, konnten sie sich eine Erlaubnis holen, dort Obst und Gemüse anzubauen. Der Anfang war schwer, denn die wenigsten glaubten an das Projekt. Um überhaupt anzufangen, wurde eine Art Zaun zum Schutz vor Dieben gebaut, der aus verschiedensten Teilen wie Reifen, Holzbrettern und Wellblechplatten&amp;nbsp;bestand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heutzutage hat sich das Projekt auf weitere Viertel ausgeweitet und zählt viele Familien, die kleine Parzellen besitzen. Einige verkaufen ihr Gemüse, andere bauen für ihren Eigenbedarf an. Auf jeden Fall sind alle Gärten mit viel Liebe gestaltet. Zu Mittag wurden wir in einen anderen Garten des Projekts eingeladen, um eine frisch zubereitete Mahlzeit mit ihrem Gemüse zu genießen – mmh! Danach ging es zurück zum Hostel, vorbei am tobenden Verkehr. Dort konnte ich den letzten Tag der „Semana del Café“ vollends genießen. Versteckt zwischen dem leckeren Duft des warmen Kaffees und der wuselnden Menschenmenge lernte ich einige interessante Menschen kennen. Unter anderem einen Tattoo-Künstler, der dabei war, den Besuchern temporäre Tattoos zum Thema Kaffee zu malen. Ich und Theo waren willkommene Gäste, denn wir plauderten mit ihm eine Weile über sein Leben und seine Arbeit in Peru, was ihm eine wohlverdiente Pause verschaffte. Im Laufe des Abends tauschte ich auch Kontakte mit ein paar Standbesitzerinnen aus, bei denen ich Pullis, eine Bauchtasche und eine neue Hose ergatterte. Denn eins muss ich mal loswerden: Ich habe furchtbar für das Jahr gepackt. Obwohl ich wirklich lange schon eine Packliste führe und mir einigermaßen sicher war, alles eingeplant zu haben, habe ich das Essentielle vergessen: Mich. Ich habe Kleidung, Spiele und anderes in Deutschland gelassen, was mir wichtig, aber vor allem nützlich war. Und wenn ich etwas dabei hatte, wie etwa Hosen und Shirts, dann leider nicht genug. Wie meine beste Freundin sagen würde: „Leben ist hart.“ Ich kann an der Situation nichts ändern, also habe ich mich damit abgefunden und&amp;nbsp;angepasst!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Tríunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240631_DxO_xJ4J3gVrZ.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of a banana Tree" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240629_DxO_tmrYuPpMN.jpg"&gt;&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Zum ersten mal gesehen: Ein&amp;nbsp;Bananenbaum&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Tríunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240636_DxO_pZkmJkSXxO.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Tríunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240638_DxO_gi_7-5bmx.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Tríunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240642_DxO_xBG7qJlfa.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Montag, 25. August&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heute hätten wir uns mit einer Frau aus der deutschen Botschaft treffen sollen, die uns mehr Infos über das Land und unseren Freiwilligenausweis geben wollte. In Peru braucht man vielerorts eine Nummer, den sogenannten &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CNI&lt;/span&gt; (código único de identificación), der auf dem Ausweis steht. Diese wird für Yape (ein digitales Zahlungsmittel, etwa wie PayPal, mit dem man so gut wie überall zahlen kann) genutzt, aber auch in Hostels und bei teuren Einkäufen verlangt. Doch das Treffen fand nie statt, da die Frau leider erkrankt war. Glück im Unglück, denn mit der gewonnenen Zeit konnten wir uns endlich &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SIM&lt;/span&gt;-Karten&amp;nbsp;kaufen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wir fuhren mit dem Bus in die Altstadt Limas. Wer sich über überfüllte U-Bahnen, Busse oder Straßenbahnen in Deutschland beschwert, wird in den Bussen Limas nicht mal einsteigen können. Die Busse waren so überfüllt, dass man sich mehr biegen und quetschen musste, als man es je in einer Runde Twister gemacht hat. Spannend war auch das Aussteigen, was einfach nur aus den Wörtern „Bajo!“ und „Pásame“&amp;nbsp;bestand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kommen wir zurück zur Altstadt: Die beeindruckenden Gebäude in der Altstadt Limas entstanden durch die spanische Kolonialherrschaft, die ab 1535 begann. Lima wurde als „Stadt der Könige“ gegründet und diente als Hauptsitz des Vizekönigs von Peru, einem der wichtigsten politischen und wirtschaftlichen Zentren des spanischen Reiches in Südamerika. Die wohlhabenden Kolonialherren, die Kirche und die Verwaltung investierten in prunkvolle Kirchen, imposante Paläste und gut erhaltene Häuser, um ihre Macht und ihren Reichtum zu demonstrieren. Dabei wurden lokale Materialien wie Ziegel, Holz und Stein genutzt und kunstvoll verarbeitet. Das spiegelte sich bei unserem Besuch dieses &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UNESCO&lt;/span&gt;-Weltkulturerbes wider. Die Altstadt war wie eine Reise in die Vergangenheit, mit der sehr gut erhaltenen Plaza Mayor, aber auch dem Besuch des San-Francisco-Klosters. Als ich auf dem Weg zu unserem nächsten Ziel durch die Gassen der Altstadt schlenderte, merkte ich auch, wie sich das Stadtbild veränderte. Zwischen der wachsenden Anzahl an Wolkenkratzern und Wohnblöcken tummelten sich noch einzelne historische Gebäude, heutzutage oft von der Regierung&amp;nbsp;genutzt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Den Abend ließen wir im „Parque de la Reserva“ ausklingen, wo wir uns zwischen Churros und Freizeitattraktionen eine Wassershow&amp;nbsp;anschauten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250008_DxO_eZP13gl30.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250032_DxO_2TchPjv8a.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250045_DxO_mWZb9FTXF.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250052_DxO_1FiPlr7_e.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250099_DxO_y5kqsrqkm.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250124_DxO_6nd8-JWpU.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250154_DxO_XMbq0_BOW.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250172_DxO_qOFtIZhz_.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250213_DxO_Pl9ZYhu-a.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260224_DxO_clMn0PQo6.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260245_DxO_vUifIVnN9.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Dienstag, 26. August&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nach einem weiteren Meeting mit Doris waren wir heute im touristischen Stadtteil „Barranco“. Wir folgten der Strandpromenade und genossen den Pazifik, in dem ich und nur wenige andere schwimmen waren. Wegen der Kälte fuhren die SchwimmerInnen mit einem Taxi zurück zum Hostel. Nachdem wir frische Empanadas gegessen hatten, genossen Jannes, Theo und ich den Rest des Abends mit einer Pizza von Pizza&amp;nbsp;Hut!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="A view of the Pacific" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260493_DxO_oWrPud-bS.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="A view of the Pacific with Limas skyscrapers and a Peruvian Flag" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260495_DxO_8yFdvy_U4.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cactuses with the Pacific in the Background" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260499_DxO_P4ImBAGCG7.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="A Closeup of a cactuses fruit" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260501_DxO_SkkT5tW59.jpg"&gt;&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Die Frucht von den Kakteen des vorherigen&amp;nbsp;Bildes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="A street in Lima leading to the Pacific in the background" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260504_DxO_GP6JGc0Tz.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="A pigeon flying over the waves of the pacific" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260510_DxO_3mTrgnlvv.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="A seagull flying over the pacific with the cityscape of Lima in the background" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260517_DxO_k_0ZP86hL.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Mittwoch, 27. August&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Für den letzten Tag war nichts geplant, nachdem wir alle zu verschiedenen Uhrzeiten Lima verließen und Doris dabei sein wollte. Erik und ich hatten am Nachmittag ein Treffen mit David, dem Chef von &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CACI&lt;/span&gt; Satinaki. Dort werden wir arbeiten und das Jahr über leben. Er hat uns viele Dinge erklärt – von den Personen, die dort leben und mit uns arbeiten werden, bis hin zu Details über Reisemöglichkeiten. Am Abend ging es für uns auch schon los. In Peru wird viel mit dem Bus gereist, wodurch der Komfort um einiges besser ist als in Deutschland. Es gibt Terminals für verschiedene Busunternehmen mit Gepäckabgabe, und die Busse an sich sind Spitze. Die Sitze sind sehr breit, komfortabel und lassen sich auf 160 bzw. 180° ausklappen. So kann man die Fahrt nach Pichanaki auf jeden Fall&amp;nbsp;genießen! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was 11 Stunden später passierte, folgt im nächsten&amp;nbsp;Post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bleib&amp;nbsp;gespannt,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buena semana y hasta la&amp;nbsp;próxima!&lt;/p&gt;</ns0:content><ns0:category term="Peru" /></ns0:entry><ns0:entry><ns0:title>Enfin?!</ns0:title><ns0:link href="https://cyprieninperu.netlify.app/fr/going-abroad/?utm_source=atomfeed" rel="alternate" /><ns0:published>2025-10-10T09:00:00-05:00</ns0:published><ns0:updated>2025-10-10T09:00:00-05:00</ns0:updated><ns0:author><ns0:name>Cyprien Chevallier</ns0:name></ns0:author><ns0:id>tag:cyprieninperu.netlify.app,2025-10-10:/fr/going-abroad/</ns0:id><ns0:summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;J&amp;#8217;ai enfin réussi à publier mon premier véritable article. J&amp;#8217;y décris mon premier jour au Pérou, jusqu&amp;#8217;à mon voyage vers ma nouvelle maison, Miguel&amp;nbsp;Grau.&lt;/p&gt;</ns0:summary><ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bien que je sois au Pérou depuis plus de trois semai- 2 mois, je n’avais encore rien publié — jusqu’à aujourd’hui ! Je vais te raconter ces quelques jours passés à Lima, qui ont servi de préparation à mon engagement à Miguel&amp;nbsp;Grau.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tout a commencé le vendredi 22 août. Ce jour-là, j’ai embarqué avec les autres volontaires dans l’avion pour Lima, avec une escale à Bogotá. Fatigués, un peu mal en point et chargés de mes trois bagages, nous sommes arrivés à 3 heures du matin à notre auberge. Le &lt;em&gt;Flying Dog&lt;/em&gt; m’a immédiatement fait réaliser dans quoi je m’étais embarquée. Notre chambre, par exemple, donnait sur une plante d’aloe Vera accrochée à un mur de briques. Nous avions un contact facile avec nos voisins de chambre (heureusement, aussi des volontaires), car le mur ne montait pas jusqu’au plafond et une fenêtre restait ouverte. Un peu plus loin dans le couloir, j’ai découvert pour la première fois les toilettes péruviennes : attention, papier toilette interdit, sous peine de boucher les canalisations ! La salle de bain, qui abritait quelques araignées et insectes en guise d’“animaux de compagnie”, avait au moins l’eau chaude… Avec le recul, rien de tout cela n’était si terrible : il suffit de s’adapter&amp;nbsp;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Samedi 23 Août&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Après quelques heures de sommeil, le programme du jour a commencé : un petit-déjeuner léger, puis une rencontre avec Doris, notre mentore locale d’Ecoselva, qui nous accompagnera toute&amp;nbsp;l’année.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L’après-midi, nous avons exploré Miraflores, l’un des quartiers les plus aisés de Lima, très touristique et où se trouvait notre auberge, ainsi que le Pacifique, dans lequel j’ai malheureusement trempé mon premier pantalon sur les quatre que j’ai&amp;nbsp;apportés…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nous avons aussi découvert les alentours de l’auberge : un bar très sympa avec d’excellents Pisco Sour, plusieurs grands espaces verts peuplés de chats errants à caresser ou à adopter, et un marché du café de plusieurs jours avec des stands variés et passionnants. Pour les repas, Ecoselva s’en occupait : déjeuner dans un restaurant arabe, dîner dans un chinois. Ce dernier n’a pas convaincu grand monde, car non seulement la nourriture était médiocre, mais en plus, poussée par une curiosité mal placée, j’ai commandé une boisson à l’aloe Vera. Imagine-toi acheter du shampoing à l’aloe vera au supermarché et y ajouter des morceaux de yaourt aux fruits : c’est exactement le goût que nous avons eu, moi et 90 % des volontaires. Mais je ne vais pas me plaindre : si notre année ne se composait que de bonnes expériences, nous nous ennuierions fermement — et je n’aurais pas d’anecdotes absurdes à partager. Comme ce scooter qui a fait irruption dans le restaurant pendant le&amp;nbsp;dîner…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of the Pacific in Lima" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230536_DxO_HipNVxR4H.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of a metal pole with a sticker and the Pacific in the background" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230540_DxO_x4EQ_uVjc.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of a road and some buildings in Lima" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230556_DxO_Ldnar9w-0I.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="The Pacific behind a beton bridge" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230559_DxO_uBmd7MWe1.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Waves of the Pacific hitting Stones" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230600_DxO_eGgQayloN.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Dimanche 24 Août&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loin des regards vigilants des forces de l’ordre et des balais des agents de nettoyage, nous avons découvert une autre facette de la ville. Lima, une métropole de 11 millions d’habitants, est marquée par le contraste entre richesse et pauvreté. Nous nous sommes rendus dans le quartier de &lt;em&gt;Villa María del Triunfo&lt;/em&gt;, un &lt;em&gt;pueblo joven&lt;/em&gt; — un quartier pauvre, habité surtout par des migrants des Andes. Le trajet fut mouvementé : ici, le code de la route est plutôt une suggestion, la ceinture de sécurité un accessoire, et le klaxon est plus utilisé que le&amp;nbsp;frein.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sur place, on nous a présenté un projet d’agriculture urbaine. Il y a une quinzaine d’années, des femmes ont décidé d’embellir le paysage local. Comme il est interdit de construire sous les pylônes électriques, elles ont obtenu l’autorisation d’y cultiver fruits et légumes. Le début fut difficile, car peu de gens croyaient en ce projet. Pour se protéger des voleurs, elles ont construit une sorte de clôture avec des pneus, des planches et des tôles&amp;nbsp;ondulées.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aujourd’hui, le projet s’est étendu à d’autres quartiers et compte de nombreuses familles qui cultivent de petites parcelles. Certaines vendent leurs légumes, d’autres cultivent pour leur consommation personnelle. Tous les jardins sont aménagés avec beaucoup d’amour. À midi, nous avons été invités dans un autre jardin du projet pour déguster un repas préparé avec leurs légumes — un délice ! Puis, retour à l’auberge, à travers le trafic chaotique. J’ai pu profiter de la dernière journée de la &lt;em&gt;Semana del Café&lt;/em&gt;, cachée parmi les effluves de café chaud et la foule animée. J’y ai rencontré des personnes intéressantes, dont un artiste tatoueur qui dessinait des tatouages éphémères sur le thème du café. Theo et moi avons discuté avec lui de sa vie et de son travail au Pérou, ce qui lui a offert une pause bien méritée. En fin de journée, j’ai aussi échangé mes coordonnées avec quelques exposantes, chez qui j’ai acheté des pulls, une banane et un nouveau pantalon. Car il faut que je l’avoue : j’ai horriblement mal préparé mes bagages. Malgré une liste minutieuse et une préparation soignée, j’ai oublié l’essentiel : moi-même. J’ai laissé en Allemagne des vêtements, des jeux et d’autres affaires importantes et utiles. Et ce que j’ai emporté, comme les pantalons et les t-shirts, n’est pas en quantité suffisante. Comme le dirait ma meilleure amie : « La vie est dure. » Je ne peux plus changer la situation, alors je m’y suis faite et je m’adapte&amp;nbsp;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Tríunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240631_DxO_xJ4J3gVrZ.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of a banana Tree" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240629_DxO_tmrYuPpMN.jpg"&gt;&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Zum ersten mal gesehen: Ein&amp;nbsp;Bananenbaum&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Tríunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240636_DxO_pZkmJkSXxO.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Tríunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240638_DxO_gi_7-5bmx.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Tríunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240642_DxO_xBG7qJlfa.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Lundi 25 Août&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nous devions rencontrer une femme de l’ambassade allemande pour obtenir des informations sur le pays et notre carte de volontaire. Au Pérou, on a souvent besoin d’un numéro, le &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CNI&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;em&gt;código único de identificación&lt;/em&gt;), qui figure sur cette carte. Il est indispensable pour utiliser Yape (un moyen de paiement numérique, comme PayPal, accepté presque partout), mais aussi pour les auberges et les achats importants. Malheureusement, la rencontre n’a pas eu lieu, car elle était malade. Tant mieux, car cela nous a permis d’acheter enfin des cartes &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SIM&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nous avons pris le bus pour le centre historique de Lima. Ceux qui se plaignent des transports en commun bondés en Allemagne ne pourraient même pas monter dans les bus de Lima. Ils étaient si pleins qu’il fallait se contorsionner plus que dans une partie de Twister. Descendre était tout aussi amusant : il suffisait de crier « ¡Bajo! » et « ¡Pásame!&amp;nbsp;».&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Revenons au centre historique : les impressionnants bâtiments datent de la colonisation espagnole, qui a commencé en 1535. Lima, fondée comme la « Cité des Rois », était le siège du vice-roi du Pérou, l’un des centres politiques et économiques les plus importants de l’Empire espagnol en Amérique du Sud. Les colons fortunés, l’Église et l’administration ont investi dans des églises somptueuses, des palais imposants et des maisons bien conservées, pour afficher leur pouvoir et leur richesse. Les matériaux locaux, comme la brique, le bois et la pierre, étaient travaillés avec art. Cela se voyait lors de notre visite de ce site classé au patrimoine mondial de l’&lt;span class="caps"&gt;UNESCO&lt;/span&gt;. Le centre historique était comme un voyage dans le temps, avec la très bien conservée Plaza Mayor et la visite du couvent San Francisco. En me promenant dans les ruelles, j’ai aussi remarqué comment le paysage urbain changeait : entre les gratte-ciel et les immeubles modernes, quelques bâtiments historiques subsistaient, souvent utilisés aujourd’hui par le&amp;nbsp;gouvernement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La soirée s’est terminée au &lt;em&gt;Parque de la Reserva&lt;/em&gt;, où nous avons assisté à un spectacle d’eau, entre churros et&amp;nbsp;attractions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250008_DxO_eZP13gl30.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250032_DxO_2TchPjv8a.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250045_DxO_mWZb9FTXF.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250052_DxO_1FiPlr7_e.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250099_DxO_y5kqsrqkm.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250124_DxO_6nd8-JWpU.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250154_DxO_XMbq0_BOW.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250172_DxO_qOFtIZhz_.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250213_DxO_Pl9ZYhu-a.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260224_DxO_clMn0PQo6.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260245_DxO_vUifIVnN9.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Mardi 26 Août&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Après une nouvelle réunion avec Doris, nous sommes allés dans le quartier touristique de Barranco. Nous avons longé la promenade en bord de mer et profité du Pacifique, dans lequel seuls quelques courageux, dont moi, ont osé se baigner. À cause du froid, les nageurs sont rentrés en taxi à l’auberge. Après avoir mangé des empanadas fraîches, Jannes, Theo et moi avons terminé la soirée avec une pizza de Pizza Hut&amp;nbsp;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="A view of the Pacific" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260493_DxO_oWrPud-bS.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="A view of the Pacific with Limas skyscrapers and a Peruvian Flag" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260495_DxO_8yFdvy_U4.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cactuses with the Pacific in the Background" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260499_DxO_P4ImBAGCG7.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="A Closeup of a cactuses fruit" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260501_DxO_SkkT5tW59.jpg"&gt;&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Les fruits des cactus de l&amp;#8217;image&amp;nbsp;précédente.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="A street in Lima leading to the Pacific in the background" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260504_DxO_GP6JGc0Tz.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="A pigeon flying over the waves of the pacific" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260510_DxO_3mTrgnlvv.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="A seagull flying over the pacific with the cityscape of Lima in the background" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260517_DxO_k_0ZP86hL.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Mercredi 27 Août&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pour ce dernier jour, rien n’était prévu, car nous quittions Lima à différents moments et Doris voulait être présente. Erik et moi avions un rendez-vous l’après-midi avec David, le directeur de &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CACI&lt;/span&gt; Satinaki, où nous allons travailler et vivre pendant un an. Il nous a expliqué beaucoup de choses : les personnes avec qui nous allons vivre et travailler, les détails sur les possibilités de voyage, etc. Le soir, nous sommes partis. Au Pérou, on voyage beaucoup en bus, et le confort est bien supérieur à celui en Allemagne. Il y a des terminaux pour différentes compagnies, avec dépôt de bagages, et les bus sont excellents : sièges larges, confortables, inclinables à 160 ou 180 degrés. Autant dire que le trajet vers Pichanaki s’annonce agréable ! Ce qui s’est passé 11 heures plus tard fera l’objet du prochain&amp;nbsp;article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reste à&amp;nbsp;l’écoute,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buena semana y hasta la&amp;nbsp;próxima!&lt;/p&gt;</ns0:content><ns0:category term="peru" /></ns0:entry><ns0:entry><ns0:title>Let the journey begin: A year in Peru</ns0:title><ns0:link href="https://cyprieninperu.netlify.app/the-adventure-begins/?utm_source=atomfeed" rel="alternate" /><ns0:published>2025-06-09T09:00:00-05:00</ns0:published><ns0:updated>2025-06-09T09:00:00-05:00</ns0:updated><ns0:author><ns0:name>Cyprien Chevallier</ns0:name></ns0:author><ns0:id>tag:cyprieninperu.netlify.app,2025-06-09:/the-adventure-begins/</ns0:id><ns0:summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;May I present myself? Cyprien, 18 years old and on the way to&amp;nbsp;peru.&lt;/p&gt;</ns0:summary><ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Cyprien, and I&amp;#8217;m the person behind this&amp;nbsp;blog. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m doing a voluntary social year (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;FSJ&lt;/span&gt;) with the association &lt;a href="https://ecoselva.org"&gt;Ecoselva&lt;/a&gt; in Miguel Grau, a very small village in the heart of the Peruvian mountain rainforest. In this blog, I want to share my experiences, insights, and travels from this fantastic&amp;nbsp;year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for more posts—I can&amp;#8217;t wait to share my adventures&amp;nbsp;here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best&amp;nbsp;regards,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyprien&lt;/p&gt;</ns0:content><ns0:category term="Peru" /></ns0:entry><ns0:entry><ns0:title>Möge die Reise beginnen: Ein Jahr in Peru</ns0:title><ns0:link href="https://cyprieninperu.netlify.app/de/the-adventure-begins/?utm_source=atomfeed" rel="alternate" /><ns0:published>2025-06-09T09:00:00-05:00</ns0:published><ns0:updated>2025-06-09T09:00:00-05:00</ns0:updated><ns0:author><ns0:name>Cyprien Chevallier</ns0:name></ns0:author><ns0:id>tag:cyprieninperu.netlify.app,2025-06-09:/de/the-adventure-begins/</ns0:id><ns0:summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Darf ich mich vorstellen? Cyprien, 18 Jahre alt und auf dem Weg nach&amp;nbsp;Peru.&lt;/p&gt;</ns0:summary><ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mein Name ist Cyprien, und ich bin die Person hinter diesem&amp;nbsp;Blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ich mache mit dem Verein &lt;a href="https://ecoselva.org"&gt;Ecoselva&lt;/a&gt; ein Freiwilliges Soziales Jahr (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;FSJ&lt;/span&gt;) in Miguel Grau, einem sehr kleinen Dorf im Herzen des peruanischen Bergregenwaldes. In diesem Blog möchte ich meine Erfahrungen, Einblicke und Reisen aus diesem fantastischen Jahr&amp;nbsp;teilen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bleib gespannt auf weitere Posts - ich kann es kaum erwarten, meine Abenteuer hier zu&amp;nbsp;teilen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liebe&amp;nbsp;Grüße,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyprien&lt;/p&gt;</ns0:content><ns0:category term="Peru" /></ns0:entry><ns0:entry><ns0:title>Que le voyage commence: Une année au Pérou</ns0:title><ns0:link href="https://cyprieninperu.netlify.app/fr/the-adventure-begins/?utm_source=atomfeed" rel="alternate" /><ns0:published>2025-06-09T09:00:00-05:00</ns0:published><ns0:updated>2025-06-09T09:00:00-05:00</ns0:updated><ns0:author><ns0:name>Cyprien Chevallier</ns0:name></ns0:author><ns0:id>tag:cyprieninperu.netlify.app,2025-06-09:/fr/the-adventure-begins/</ns0:id><ns0:summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Puis-je me presenter? Cyprien, 18 ans et en route pour le&amp;nbsp;Pérou.&lt;/p&gt;</ns0:summary><ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Salut,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Je m&amp;#8217;appelle Cyprien, et je suis la personne derrière ce&amp;nbsp;blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Je fais une année de volontariat social (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;FSJ&lt;/span&gt;) avec l&amp;#8217;association &lt;a href="https://ecoselva.org/"&gt;Ecoselva&lt;/a&gt;. Je serais à Miguel Grau, un tout petit village au cœur de la forêt amazonienne péruvienne. Sur ce blog, je souhaite partager mes expériences, mes découvertes et mes voyages au cours de cette année&amp;nbsp;fantastique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reste attentif à d&amp;#8217;autres posts, car je suis impatient de partager mes aventures avec toi&amp;nbsp;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bises,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyprien&lt;/p&gt;</ns0:content><ns0:category term="Peru" /></ns0:entry></ns0:feed>