<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ns0:feed xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><ns0:title>Cyprien in Peru</ns0:title><ns0:link href="https://cyprieninperu.netlify.app/" rel="alternate" /><ns0:link href="https://cyprieninperu.netlify.app/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self" /><ns0:id>https://cyprieninperu.netlify.app/</ns0:id><ns0:updated>2025-11-29T00:00:00-05:00</ns0:updated><ns0:entry><ns0:title>11 hours later…</ns0:title><ns0:link href="https://cyprieninperu.netlify.app/11-hours-later/?utm_source=atomfeed" rel="alternate" /><ns0:published>2025-11-29T00:00:00-05:00</ns0:published><ns0:updated>2025-11-29T00:00:00-05:00</ns0:updated><ns0:author><ns0:name>Cyprien Chevallier</ns0:name></ns0:author><ns0:id>tag:cyprieninperu.netlify.app,2025-11-29:/11-hours-later/</ns0:id><ns0:summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Arrival in Miguel Grau, discovering our rooms and the village square. In this article, I tell you about the end of our bus journey and our first days in the&amp;nbsp;village.&lt;/p&gt;</ns0:summary><ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;… we finally arrived at the Movílbus terminal in Pichanaki. It was around 7 in the morning, but the city of 20,000 inhabitants had long been awake. All kinds of vehicles—mototaxis, pick-up trucks, and small lorries—zipped along the multilane main road. The air was filled with swirling dust and the acrid exhaust of the traffic. Tired but excited, Erik and I waited for Aurelia, with whom I’d been coordinating our&amp;nbsp;arrival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the outside, the terminal looked like a garage, but inside it had a few rows of seats and a small counter. About an hour later, a dark grey pick-up truck arrived, with Aurelia and a few others inside. So here they were—the team we were going to live and work with for an entire&amp;nbsp;year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elvis, in his forties, describes himself as a happy man: “As long as there’s beer, coffee, and women.” A rock-’n’-roll fan who’s rarely seen without his&amp;nbsp;motorcycle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aurelia, head of the quality-control lab, Q-Grader for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CACI&lt;/span&gt; Satinaki for the past eight years, and mother to Mavi. She always has the lab’s best coffee and best&amp;nbsp;chocolate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blanca, our host mother for the year, who feeds us with her cooking and helps us settle into her&amp;nbsp;home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mavi, part-time princess, who brings joy and sunshine to the lab every&amp;nbsp;day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We enjoyed a wonderful breakfast and chatted together. The food was delicious: bread, eggs, and yuca, a root vegetable with a potato-like flavor. Fried yuca is even better—crispy on the outside, soft on the inside. A real&amp;nbsp;treat!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About an hour later, we were already on the road to Yurinaki. During the drive, we made a brief stop by the roadside, where a small wooden hut with a leaf roof was selling coconuts “to go.” Apart from Erik and me, no one seemed surprised by this improvised drive-through. After another hour on the road and a brand-new drink in hand, we reached Yurinaki, the closest town to Miguel Grau. Without much explanation—a cultural habit I’d soon have to get used to—we made a short stop there. Erik and I took the chance to explore the surroundings a bit, without straying too far into this still-unknown&amp;nbsp;territory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The town of about 1,500 inhabitants has at its center a beautiful green park with a stone stage in the middle. A road circles around it, lined with small shops and&amp;nbsp;restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later4_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432200069"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then left Yurinaki on a small road leading into the mountains. Far from the dense traffic of the cities, the air was pleasant: the sun warmed our skin, birds chirped in the trees, and a light breeze brushed our faces through the open windows. After about forty minutes of driving—punctuated by anecdotes and incredible views—we arrived at Blanca’s house. It’s an old stone house with a corrugated-metal roof. Several wooden structures scattered around shelter chickens, geese, and friends—plus an old Jeep and a workshop full of&amp;nbsp;tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of us would stay in the only room on the first floor, while the other would stay in David’s newer, more modern house. This second house, only a few minutes away, looks a lot like a European home, with a large terrace and several rooms with private bathrooms on the upper&amp;nbsp;floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I was supposed to sleep in the newer house, we had to swap rooms quickly because of Erik’s allergies. I have to admit that this change was tough for me at first. For those who know me: I’m not exactly a fan of insects. And this “new” room had practically no insulation—no glass window, just a plastic tarp for a ceiling. I quickly came into contact with all sorts of insects: a wasp stung me right in the chest, mosquitoes swarmed around my bed, and so on. Fortunately, I soon got a mosquito net and began to slowly (very slowly) get used to these little creatures. Ah, and the chickens? Unforgettable—especially their 3-a.m. alarm clock&amp;nbsp;routine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Arrival in Miguel Grau" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later13_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432252461"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Davids Haus" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later2_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432254148"&gt;&lt;p class="caption"&gt;David’s&amp;nbsp;house&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="3/5 Katzen von Blanca" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later7_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432233749"&gt;&lt;p class="caption"&gt;3 of Blanca’s 5&amp;nbsp;cats&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Hühner und Gänse" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later3_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432261528"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later0_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432256028"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, these first days were fantastic: discovering the lab, our work, meeting new friends, and getting our first introduction to Peruvian cuisine—which I’ll write more about in a separate article. The immersion is complete, and it’s genuinely fascinating to discover this new culture, one I knew nothing about before. I’ll let the next photos speak for&amp;nbsp;themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;¡Buenos días y hasta la&amp;nbsp;próxima!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyprien&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later15_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432239540"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later11_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432216274"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later14_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432232078"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later16_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432244024"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later12_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432257686"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later8_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432201490"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;</ns0:content><ns0:category term="peru" /></ns0:entry><ns0:entry><ns0:title>11 Stunden später…</ns0:title><ns0:link href="https://cyprieninperu.netlify.app/de/11-hours-later/?utm_source=atomfeed" rel="alternate" /><ns0:published>2025-11-29T00:00:00-05:00</ns0:published><ns0:updated>2025-11-29T00:00:00-05:00</ns0:updated><ns0:author><ns0:name>Cyprien Chevallier</ns0:name></ns0:author><ns0:id>tag:cyprieninperu.netlify.app,2025-11-29:/de/11-hours-later/</ns0:id><ns0:summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ankunft in Miguel Grau, Entdeckung unserer Zimmer und des Dorfplatzes. In diesem Artikel erzähle ich euch vom Ende unserer Busreise und von unseren ersten Tagen im&amp;nbsp;Dorf.&lt;/p&gt;</ns0:summary><ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;… sind wir im Movílbus-Terminal in Pichanaki angekommen. Es war ungefähr 7 Uhr morgens, doch die Stadt mit 20.000 Einwohnern war schon längst wach. Verschiedenste Fahrzeuge – Mototaxis, Pick-ups und kleine Lastwagen – düsten durch die mehrspurige Hauptstraße. Die Luft war erfüllt von aufgewirbeltem Staub und den stinkenden Abgasen der Autos. Müde und voller Vorfreude warteten Erik und ich auf Aurelia, mit der ich in Kontakt war, um unsere Ankunft zu&amp;nbsp;organisieren.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Der Terminal, in dem wir warteten, sah von außen aus wie eine Garage, doch innen war er mit ein paar Sitzreihen und einer Theke ausgestattet. Etwa eine Stunde später kam ein dunkelgrauer Pick-up, in dem Aurelia und ein paar andere Personen saßen. Hier ist also die Mannschaft, mit der wir ein Jahr lang leben und arbeiten&amp;nbsp;werden:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elvis, in den Vierzigern, beschreibt sich selbst als glücklichen Mann: „Wenn es Bier, Kaffee und Frauen gibt.“ Ein Rock-’n’-Roll-Fan, der selten ohne sein Motorrad zu sehen&amp;nbsp;ist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aurelia, die Chefin des Labors für Qualitätskontrolle, Q-Graderin seit acht Jahren für &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CACI&lt;/span&gt; Satinaki und die Mutter von Mavi. Sie hat immer den besten Kaffee und die beste Schokolade des&amp;nbsp;Labors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blanca, unsere Gastmutter für dieses Jahr, die uns mit ihrer Küche versorgt und hilft, uns in ihrem Haus&amp;nbsp;zurechtzufinden.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mavi, Prinzessin in Teilzeit, die immer Freude und Sonnenschein ins Labor&amp;nbsp;bringt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mit diesen lieben Menschen haben wir ein tolles Frühstück genossen und geplaudert. Das Essen war richtig lecker: Brot, Eier und Yuca, eine Wurzel mit einem Geschmack, der dem der Kartoffel ähnelt. Frittiert ist Yuca jedoch viel besser: außen knusprig, innen weich – ein&amp;nbsp;Schmaus!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ungefähr eine Stunde später waren wir bereits auf dem Weg nach Yurinaki. Wir hielten während der Fahrt kurz am Straßenrand, wo ein kleines Haus aus Holz mit einem Blätterdach Kokosnüsse „to go“ anbot. Außer Erik und mir schien niemand von diesem improvisierten Drive-through überrascht zu sein. Nach etwa einer weiteren Stunde Fahrt und dem neuen Getränk erreichten wir Yurinaki, die nächstgelegene Stadt zu Miguel Grau. Ohne viel Erklärung – eine kulturelle Gewohnheit, an die ich mich gewöhnen musste – machten wir dort eine kurze Pause. Erik und ich erkundeten ein wenig die Umgebung, ohne uns zu weit in dieses unbekannte Territorium vorzuwagen.
Die Stadt mit etwa 1.500 Einwohnern besteht im Zentrum aus einem schönen grünen Park mit einer steinernen Bühne in der Mitte. Eine Straße umrundet diesen, gesäumt von kleinen Läden und Restaurants am&amp;nbsp;Rand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later4_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432200069"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anschließend verließen wir Yurinaki auf einer kleinen Straße, die in die Berge führte. Weit entfernt vom dichten Verkehr der Städte war die Luft angenehm: Die Sonne erwärmte unsere Haut, die Vögel zwitscherten in den Bäumen, und eine leichte Brise kitzelte durch die offenen Fenster unsere Gesichter. Nach ungefähr 40 Minuten Fahrt, verschönert durch Anekdoten und unglaubliche Aussichten, kamen wir bei Blancas Haus an. Es handelt sich um ein altes Steinhaus mit einem Wellblechdach. Einige Holzkonstruktionen in der Umgebung schützen Hühner, Gänse und Co. sowie einen alten Jeep und ein mit Werkzeugen gefülltes&amp;nbsp;Atelier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Einer von uns beiden sollte im einzigen Zimmer der ersten Etage wohnen, der andere im neueren und moderneren Haus von David. Das nur wenige Minuten entfernte Haus ähnelt stark einem europäischen Haus, wie ich es kenne, mit einer großen Terrasse und mehreren Zimmern mit eigenem Bad im ersten&amp;nbsp;Stock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obwohl ich in diesem neueren Haus schlafen sollte, mussten wir wegen Eriks Allergien schnell die Zimmer tauschen. Ich muss zugeben, dass dieser Wechsel für mich zu Beginn schwierig war. Für die, die mich kennen: Ich bin kein großer Freund von Insekten. Und in diesem neuen Zimmer fehlt die Isolation nach außen – es gibt keine Fensterscheibe und nur eine Plastikplane als Decke. Schnell kam ich also in Kontakt mit allen möglichen Insekten: Eine Wespe stach mich mitten in den Oberkörper, Mücken wirbelten um mein Bett herum, usw. Glücklicherweise bekam ich schnell ein Moskitonetz für mein Bett und konnte mich langsam, aber sicher an diese kleinen Viecher gewöhnen. Ah, und die Hühner? Unvergesslich, mit ihrem Wecker um 3 Uhr morgens durch ihr lautes&amp;nbsp;Krähen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Ankunft in Miguel Grau" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later13_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432252461"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Davids Haus" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later2_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432254148"&gt;&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Davids&amp;nbsp;Haus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="3/5 Katzen von Blanca" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later7_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432233749"&gt;&lt;p class="caption"&gt;3 von 5&amp;nbsp;Katzen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Hühner und Gänse" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later3_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432261528"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later0_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432256028"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zusammengefasst waren diese ersten Tage trotzdem fantastisch: die Entdeckung des Labors, unserer Arbeit, das Kennenlernen neuer Freunde und die Einführung in die peruanische Küche, von der ich in einem separaten Artikel berichten werde. Die Immersion ist vollständig, und es ist wirklich interessant, diese neue, mir bisher unbekannte Kultur zu entdecken. Ich lasse nun die nächsten Bilder für sich&amp;nbsp;sprechen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;¡Buenos días y hasta la&amp;nbsp;próxima!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyprien&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later15_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432239540"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later11_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432216274"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later14_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432232078"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later16_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432244024"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later12_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432257686"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later8_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432201490"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;</ns0:content><ns0:category term="peru" /></ns0:entry><ns0:entry><ns0:title>11 heures plus tard…</ns0:title><ns0:link href="https://cyprieninperu.netlify.app/fr/11-hours-later/?utm_source=atomfeed" rel="alternate" /><ns0:published>2025-11-29T00:00:00-05:00</ns0:published><ns0:updated>2025-11-29T00:00:00-05:00</ns0:updated><ns0:author><ns0:name>Cyprien Chevallier</ns0:name></ns0:author><ns0:id>tag:cyprieninperu.netlify.app,2025-11-29:/fr/11-hours-later/</ns0:id><ns0:summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Arrivée à Miguel Grau, découverte de nos chambres et de la place du village. Dans cet article, je raconte notre fin de voyage en bus et nos premiers jours à Miguel&amp;nbsp;Grau.&lt;/p&gt;</ns0:summary><ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;… nous sommes arrivés au terminal de Movílbus à Pichanaki. Il était environ 7 heures du matin, mais ça faisait belle lurette que la ville de 20 000 habitants ne dormait plus. La circulation sur la route principale était dense, composée de petits moto-taxis bleus, de pick-up et de camionnettes, probablement en route pour le travail.  L’air était rempli de poussière, mêlée à l’odeur des gaz d’échappement.
Fatigués mais remplis d&amp;#8217;anticipation joyeuse, Erik et moi avons attendu Aurélia, avec qui j’étais en contact pour organiser notre arrivée.
Le terminal, où on attendait, ressemblait de l’extérieur plutôt à un garage, mais avec des sièges et un comptoir à l’intérieur pour patienter.
Après environ une heure d’attente, un pick-up gris-foncé s’est arrêté devant nous. À l’intérieur se trouvaient Aurélia et quelques autres personnes. Voici donc l’équipe avec laquelle nous allons vivre et travailler pendant un an&amp;nbsp;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elvis, la quarantaine, se décrit comme un homme heureux : « S’il a de la bière, du café et des femmes. » Fan de rock’n’roll de la première heure, il ne sort jamais sans sa&amp;nbsp;moto.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aurélia, cheffe du laboratoire de contrôle qualité, Q-Gradeuse depuis huit ans pour &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CACI&lt;/span&gt; Satinaki et maman de Mavi. Elle a toujours le meilleur café et le meilleur chocolat du&amp;nbsp;laboratoire.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blanca, notre hôte pour cette année, qui nous régale avec sa cuisine et nous aide à nous repérer dans sa&amp;nbsp;maison.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mavi, princesse à temps partiel et fille d’Aurélia, qui apporte joie et bonne humeur au&amp;nbsp;laboratoire.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C’est avec cette équipe que nous avons pris un bon petit-déjeuner et discuté. Le repas était délicieux : du pain, des œufs et du yucca, une racine au goût similaire à celui de la pomme de terre, mais bien supérieure une fois frite — croustillante à l’extérieur et moelleuse à l’intérieur. Un régal !
Environ une heure plus tard, nous avons pris la route pour Puerto Yurinaki. En chemin, nous nous sommes arrêtés en bord de route, où une petite maison en bois avec un toit de chaume proposait des noix de coco à emporter. À part Erik et moi, personne ne semblait surpris par ce service improvisé. Après une heure de route et avec notre nouvelle boisson, nous sommes arrivés à Yurinaki, la ville la plus proche de Miguel Grau. Sans trop d’explications — une habitude culturelle à laquelle j’ai dû m’habituer —, nous y avons fait une halte. Erik et moi avons exploré un peu les alentours, sans nous aventurer trop loin sur cette terre inconnue. Le centre de la ville à 1 500 habitants est composée d’un joli parc, avec une scène en pierre. Une route en fait le tour, bordée de petits magasins et de&amp;nbsp;restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later4_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432200069"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nous avons ensuite quitté Yurinaki et pris la petite route qui mène aux villages dans les montagnes. Loin de la circulation dense des grandes villes, l’air était agréable : le soleil réchauffait notre peau, les oiseaux chantaient dans les arbres et une brise légère nous caressait le visage. Après 40 minutes de trajet, entrecoupées d’anecdotes et de paysages incroyables, nous sommes arrivés à la maison de Blanca. Il s’agit d’une vieille bâtisse en pierre, avec un toit en tôle ondulée. Les quelques constructions en bois aux alentours abritent des poules, des oies et d’autres animaux, ainsi qu’un vieux Jeep et un atelier rempli d’outils.
L’un d’entre nous devait dormir dans la seule chambre du deuxième étage, tandis que l’autre logeait dans la maison plus récente et moderne de David, à quelques minutes à pied. Celle-ci ressemble davantage à une maison européenne, avec une grande terrasse et plusieurs chambres à l’étage, chacune dotée de sa propre salle de bain.
Bien que j’aurais dû dormir chez David, nous avons rapidement échangé nos chambres en raison des allergies d’Erik. Je dois avouer qu’au début, ce changement a été difficile pour moi. Pour ceux qui me connaissent, je ne suis pas fan des insectes. Dans cette nouvelle chambre, il n’y avait pas d&amp;#8217;isolation extérieure, il manquait un carreau et une bâche faisait office de plafond. Je me suis donc rapidement retrouvé en compagnie de toutes sortes d’insectes : une guêpe m’a piqué en plein torse, des moustiques tournoyaient autour de mon lit, etc. Heureusement, j’ai rapidement reçu une moustiquaire pour mon lit et je me suis peu à peu habitué à la présence de ces petites bêtes. Ah, et les coqs ? Impossible de les oublier : les réveils matinaux à 3 h du matin, avec leurs cocoricos&amp;nbsp;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="L'arrivée à Miguel Grau" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later13_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432252461"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="La maison de David" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later2_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432254148"&gt;&lt;p class="caption"&gt;La maison de&amp;nbsp;David&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Des chats de Blanca" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later7_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432233749"&gt;&lt;p class="caption"&gt;3 sur 5 Chats de&amp;nbsp;Blanca&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Des poules et des oies" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later3_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432261528"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later0_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432256028"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En somme, ces premiers jours ont été vraiment formidables : découverte du laboratoire, de notre travail, rencontre de nouveaux amis et initiation à la cuisine péruvienne, sur laquelle je reviendrai dans un article séparé. L&amp;#8217;immersion est complète et c&amp;#8217;est vraiment intéressant de découvrir toute cette culture qui m&amp;#8217;était inconnue. Je vais laisser les prochaines images parler à ma place pour montrer la beauté de cet&amp;nbsp;endroit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;¡Buenos días y hasta la&amp;nbsp;próxima!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyprien&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later15_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432239540"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later11_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432216274"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later14_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432232078"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later16_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432244024"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later12_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432257686"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later8_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432201490"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;</ns0:content><ns0:category term="peru" /></ns0:entry><ns0:entry><ns0:title>Finally?!</ns0:title><ns0:link href="https://cyprieninperu.netlify.app/going-abroad/?utm_source=atomfeed" rel="alternate" /><ns0:published>2025-10-27T09:00:00-05:00</ns0:published><ns0:updated>2025-10-27T09:00:00-05:00</ns0:updated><ns0:author><ns0:name>Cyprien Chevallier</ns0:name></ns0:author><ns0:id>tag:cyprieninperu.netlify.app,2025-10-27:/going-abroad/</ns0:id><ns0:summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve finally managed to publish my first proper article. In it, I describe my first days in Peru, from arriving in Lima to traveling to my new home in Miguel&amp;nbsp;Grau.&lt;/p&gt;</ns0:summary><ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Although I have now been in Peru for more than two months, I haven’t managed to publish a single article so far – until now. Today, I’d like to look back on the few days we spent in Lima, which served as preparation for my placement in Miguel&amp;nbsp;Grau.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything began on Friday, August 22. The departure for the twenty other volunteers and me was scheduled for 2:45 p.m., flying from Frankfurt to Lima via Bogotá. Exhausted, occasionally travel-sick, and burdened with my three-piece luggage, we arrived at around three in the morning at our hostel in Lima, the &lt;em&gt;Flying Dog&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing that made us laugh was the room layout, which still felt completely absurd to us at that point. One of the windows, for example, looked straight onto an aloe vera plant hanging against a brick wall. We quickly got in touch with our neighbors—fortunately also volunteers—since the wall between the rooms didn’t reach the ceiling and even had an open window built into&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After only a few hours of sleep, our schedule resumed on Sunday morning. We met Doris, our national coordinator from Ecoselva, who would be accompanying us throughout the year. We spent several hours in a meeting room, where she shared a wide range of information about the year ahead and our stay in Lima. Although we had already completed a ten-day preparation seminar before departure, this meeting proved extremely helpful—especially because Doris shared her many years of experience living in&amp;nbsp;Peru.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon, we explored Miraflores, one of Lima’s more affluent districts. It is heavily oriented toward tourism and also the neighborhood where our hostel was located. This was where I saw the Pacific Ocean for the first time—and, unfortunately, where I soaked my first and nicest of the four pairs of trousers I had brought with me in salty&amp;nbsp;seawater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also explored the area around the hostel: a small bar serving excellent pisco sours, several large green parks with free-roaming cats that you could pet (and, at least in theory, even adopt), and the multi-day coffee market known as &lt;em&gt;Semana del Café&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During these preparation days, our meals were organized by Ecoselva. We had lunch at an Arab restaurant and dinner at a Chinese one. The latter, unfortunately, didn’t convince most of us. Looking back, I’m sure we would handle it much better today. It was less a matter of taste than of adjustment—our bodies and expectations simply hadn’t arrived in Peru&amp;nbsp;yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding to this was the fact that I had suggested ordering an aloe vera drink, so that we could try everything that was on offer. That drink didn’t quite match our taste at the time, and the restaurant ended up with a rather mixed reputation within our group—probably also because everything felt so&amp;nbsp;unexpected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of the Pacific in Lima" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230536_DxO_HipNVxR4H.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of a metal pole with a sticker and the Pacific in the background" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230540_DxO_x4EQ_uVjc.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of a road and some buildings in Lima" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230556_DxO_Ldnar9w-0I.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="The Pacific behind a concrete bridge" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230559_DxO_uBmd7MWe1.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Waves of the Pacific hitting stones" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230600_DxO_eGgQayloN.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Sunday, August 24,&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Far from the watchful eyes of security guards and the sweeping brooms of cleaning crews, we discovered a different side of Lima today: a city of around eleven million inhabitants, marked by stark social&amp;nbsp;contrasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We traveled to the district of Villa María del Triunfo, a so-called &lt;em&gt;pueblo joven&lt;/em&gt;—a structurally disadvantaged neighborhood, primarily inhabited by migrants from the Andes and often built through grassroots initiative. The journey itself was rough: in Peru, traffic laws are more of a suggestion, seatbelts are often decorative, and the horn is used far more frequently than the brake. For us newcomers from Germany, it initially felt chaotic, but it is simply part of everyday life&amp;nbsp;here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On site, we were introduced to a project focused on urban agriculture. Around fifteen years ago, a group of women decided to make their surroundings more livable. Since construction is prohibited beneath high-voltage power lines, they obtained permission to grow fruits and vegetables there instead. The beginnings were difficult, as few people believed in the project’s success. To get started at all, they built a makeshift fence out of tires, wooden planks, and corrugated metal to protect the gardens from&amp;nbsp;theft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, the project has expanded to several neighborhoods and includes many families cultivating small plots of land. Some sell their produce, while others grow food solely for their own consumption. What they all share is the care and dedication invested in their gardens. At lunchtime, we were invited to another project garden to enjoy a freshly prepared meal made from homegrown vegetables—an absolute&amp;nbsp;highlight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterward, we returned to the hostel, moving from the quiet, communal gardens back into the busy, noisy streets of Miraflores. There, I was able to fully enjoy the final day of &lt;em&gt;Semana del Café&lt;/em&gt;. Hidden between the warm aroma of coffee and the bustling crowd, I met several interesting people, including a tattoo artist who was creating temporary coffee-themed tattoos for visitors. Theo and I were welcome conversation partners, and we spent quite some time talking with him about his life and work in Peru—giving him a well-earned break from the market’s constant&amp;nbsp;activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later that evening, I also exchanged contact details with a few stallholders, from whom I bought sweaters, a waist bag, and a new pair of trousers. One thing became very clear during these days: when packing for the year ahead, I hadn’t always made the best&amp;nbsp;decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had carefully kept a packing list and eventually ended up with one that included everything I truly needed. But shortly before departure, I suddenly began negotiating that list with myself—using surprisingly poor arguments. Sweaters? I don’t need that many. Games? Who would I play with in a small village? Warm hiking clothes? I won’t be doing that in Peru. Well… I was very wrong and had to come up with creative stopgap&amp;nbsp;solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Triunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240631_DxO_xJ4J3gVrZ.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of a banana tree" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240629_DxO_tmrYuPpMN.jpg"&gt;&lt;p class="caption"&gt;The first time I had ever seen a banana&amp;nbsp;tree&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Triunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240636_DxO_pZkmJkSXxO.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Triunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240638_DxO_gi_7-5bmx.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Triunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240642_DxO_xBG7qJlfa.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Monday, August 25,&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were supposed to meet a staff member from the German embassy today, who would provide us with further information about the country and our volunteer IDs. In Peru, many everyday processes require an identification number known as the &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. It is used for Yape—a digital payment method comparable to PayPal—as well as in hostels or for larger&amp;nbsp;purchases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meeting was canceled at short notice because the staff member fell ill. A blessing in disguise: with the extra time, we were able to buy &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SIM&lt;/span&gt; cards and finally reconnect with the outside world. We were now more independent and could move around the city more&amp;nbsp;freely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We took the bus to Lima’s historic center. Anyone who complains about overcrowded buses or subways in Germany wouldn’t even manage to get on a bus in Lima. They were so packed that you had to twist and squeeze more than in a game of Twister. Getting off the bus was an experience in itself, usually consisting of little more than the words “¡Bajo!” and&amp;nbsp;“Pásame.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The historic center itself impressed me deeply. Most of the buildings date back to the period of Spanish colonial rule, which began in 1535. Lima was founded as the “City of Kings” and long served as the seat of the Viceroy of Peru—one of the most important political and economic centers of the Spanish Empire in South America. The Church, the administration, and wealthy colonial elites invested in grand churches, imposing palaces, and richly decorated homes, using local materials such as brick, wood, and stone. All of this is clearly reflected in this &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UNESCO&lt;/span&gt; World Heritage&amp;nbsp;Site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ended the evening at Parque de la Reserva, where we watched an impressive fountain show while enjoying churros and fairground&amp;nbsp;attractions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250008_DxO_eZP13gl30.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250032_DxO_2TchPjv8a.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250045_DxO_mWZb9FTXF.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250052_DxO_1FiPlr7_e.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250099_DxO_y5kqsrqkm.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250124_DxO_6nd8-JWpU.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250154_DxO_XMbq0_BOW.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250172_DxO_qOFtIZhz_.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250213_DxO_Pl9ZYhu-a.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260224_DxO_clMn0PQo6.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260245_DxO_vUifIVnN9.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Tuesday, August 26,&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After another meeting with Doris, we visited the tourist district of Barranco today. We followed the coastal promenade and enjoyed the view of the Pacific, where I went swimming along with only a few others. Because of the cold, the swimmers later returned to the hostel by taxi. In the evening, we had empanadas—pastry pockets filled with cheese, chicken, or vegetables. For me, they were a good substitute for the kebab I wouldn’t be enjoying for the next&amp;nbsp;year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the final day, nothing else was planned, as everyone was leaving Lima at different times and Doris wanted to be present for all departures. In the afternoon, Erik and I met David, the head of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CACI&lt;/span&gt; Satinaki—the place where we would live and work. He explained many things to us, from the people there to travel opportunities during the&amp;nbsp;year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That same evening, we set off. Long-distance travel in Peru is largely done by bus, and the level of comfort is noticeably higher than in Germany. There are large terminals with luggage check-in, and the buses themselves are surprisingly comfortable: wide seats, plenty of legroom, and backrests that recline up to 160 or even 180 degrees. The eleven-hour journey to Pichanaki was therefore quite&amp;nbsp;enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happened there will follow in the next&amp;nbsp;post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back, those first days were overwhelming—but wonderful. Whether it was city life, the food, or the stark contrasts between different neighborhoods, I slowly realized that I had arrived in a culture unfamiliar to me, one in which I would spend an entire year. A year I’m genuinely looking forward to—for precisely that reason: cultural&amp;nbsp;exchange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stay tuned,
Buena semana y hasta la&amp;nbsp;próxima!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</ns0:content><ns0:category term="peru" /></ns0:entry><ns0:entry><ns0:title>Es geht los!</ns0:title><ns0:link href="https://cyprieninperu.netlify.app/de/going-abroad/?utm_source=atomfeed" rel="alternate" /><ns0:published>2025-10-27T09:00:00-05:00</ns0:published><ns0:updated>2025-10-27T09:00:00-05:00</ns0:updated><ns0:author><ns0:name>Cyprien Chevallier</ns0:name></ns0:author><ns0:id>tag:cyprieninperu.netlify.app,2025-10-27:/de/going-abroad/</ns0:id><ns0:summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Endlich habe ich es geschafft, meinen ersten richtigen Artikel zu veröffentlichen. Ich beschreibe meinen ersten Tag in Peru bis hin zu meiner Reise in meine neue Heimat Miguel&amp;nbsp;Grau.&lt;/p&gt;</ns0:summary><ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Obwohl ich nun schon seit mehr als zwei Monaten in Peru bin, habe ich es bislang nicht geschafft, auch nur einen einzigen Artikel zu veröffentlichen – bis jetzt. Heute möchte ich von den wenigen Tagen in Lima berichten, die als Vorbereitung für meinen Einsatz in Miguel Grau&amp;nbsp;dienten.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alles begann am Freitag, dem 22. August. Um 14:45 Uhr war der Abflug für mich und die 20 anderen Freiwilligen geplant: von Frankfurt nach Lima über Bogotá. Mit viel Müdigkeit, Reisekrankheit und meinem dreiteiligen Gepäck kamen wir gegen drei Uhr morgens in unserem Hostel, dem &lt;em&gt;Flying Dog&lt;/em&gt;, in Lima&amp;nbsp;an.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Das Erste, worüber wir lachen mussten, war die für uns noch absurde Zimmergestaltung. Unter anderem hatte unser Zimmer ein Fenster mit Blick auf eine Aloe-Vera-Pflanze, die an einer Backsteinmauer hing. Zu unseren Zimmernachbarn, zum Glück ebenfalls andere Freiwillige, hatten wir schnell Kontakt, da die Wand nicht bis zur Decke reichte und ein offenes Fenster in sie eingelassen&amp;nbsp;war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nach wenigen Stunden Schlaf ging es direkt mit unserem Tagesprogramm am Sonntag weiter. Am Morgen trafen wir uns mit Doris, unserer Landesmentorin von Ecoselva, die uns das ganze Jahr über begleiten sollte. Wir verbrachten mehrere Stunden in einem Besprechungszimmer, wo uns zahlreiche Informationen über das Jahr und unseren Aufenthalt in Lima vermittelt wurden. Zwar hatten wir bereits ein zehntägiges Vorbereitungsseminar vor dem Flug absolviert, doch diese Besprechung war dennoch sehr hilfreich. Vor allem, weil Doris ihre langjährigen Lebenserfahrungen in Peru mit uns&amp;nbsp;teilte.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Im Laufe des Nachmittags entdeckten wir Miraflores, eines der wohlhabenderen Viertel Limas. Es ist stark auf Tourismus ausgerichtet und auch der Stadtteil, in dem unser Hostel lag. Zum ersten Mal sah ich den Pazifik, in dem ich leider auch meine erste und schönste von insgesamt vier Hosen mit Salzwasser&amp;nbsp;tränkte.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wir erkundeten außerdem die Umgebung des Hostels: eine kleine Bar mit gutem Pisco Sour, mehrere große Grünanlagen mit freilaufenden Katzen, die man streicheln (und theoretisch sogar adoptieren) konnte, sowie dem mehrtägigen Kaffeemarkt &lt;em&gt;Semana del Café&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Für unsere Verpflegung war während der Vorbereitungstage Ecoselva zuständig. So aßen wir mittags in einem arabischen Restaurant und abends in einem chinesischen. Von Letzterem waren leider die wenigsten überzeugt. Heute bin ich mir sicher, dass wir damit inzwischen deutlich besser zurechtkommen würden. Rückblickend war es weniger eine Frage des Geschmacks als der Gewöhnung – unsere Körper und Erwartungen waren schlicht noch nicht in Peru&amp;nbsp;angekommen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hinzu kam, dass ich dazu aufgerufen hatte, ein Aloe-Vera-Getränk zu bestellen, damit wir möglichst alles probieren, was uns angeboten wurde. Doch dieses Getränk traf unseren Geschmack in diesem Moment eher nicht, und so bekam das Restaurant in unserer Runde einen schlechteren Ruf, wohl auch, weil alles sehr unerwartet&amp;nbsp;kam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of the Pacific in Lima" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230536_DxO_HipNVxR4H.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of a metal pole with a sticker and the Pacific in the background" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230540_DxO_x4EQ_uVjc.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of a road and some buildings in Lima" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230556_DxO_Ldnar9w-0I.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="The Pacific behind a beton bridge" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230559_DxO_uBmd7MWe1.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Waves of the Pacific hitting Stones" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230600_DxO_eGgQayloN.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Sonntag, 24. August&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weit entfernt vom wachsamen Auge der Sicherheitskräfte und den säubernden Besen der Putzkräfte entdeckten wir heute eine neue Facette Limas: eine Stadt mit rund elf Millionen Einwohnern, geprägt von starken sozialen&amp;nbsp;Gegensätzen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wir fuhren in das Viertel Villa María del Triunfo, ein sogenanntes pueblo joven – ein strukturell benachteiligtes Viertel, das vor allem von Migrant:innen aus den Anden bewohnt wird und vielerorts durch Eigeninitiative entstanden ist. Unser Weg dorthin war holprig: In Peru ist die Straßenverkehrsordnung eher eine Empfehlung, der Sicherheitsgurt oft Dekoration und die Hupe wird deutlich häufiger benutzt als die Bremse. Für uns als Neuankömmlinge aus Deutschland wirkte das zunächst chaotisch, gehört hier jedoch ganz selbstverständlich zum&amp;nbsp;Alltag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vor Ort wurde uns ein Projekt der urbanen Agrikultur vorgestellt. Vor etwa 15 Jahren hatten sich einige Frauen dazu entschieden, die Umgebung lebenswerter zu gestalten. Da unter Strommasten ein Bauverbot gilt, erhielten sie die Erlaubnis, dort Obst und Gemüse anzubauen. Der Anfang war schwierig, denn nur wenige glaubten an den Erfolg des Projekts. Um überhaupt starten zu können, errichteten sie einen einfachen Schutzzaun aus Reifen, Holzbrettern und&amp;nbsp;Wellblechplatten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heute hat sich das Projekt auf weitere Viertel ausgeweitet und umfasst zahlreiche Familien, die kleine Parzellen bewirtschaften. Einige verkaufen ihr Gemüse, andere bauen ausschließlich für den Eigenbedarf an. Allen gemeinsam ist, wie viel Sorgfalt und Liebe in den Gärten steckt. Zum Mittagessen wurden wir in einen weiteren Garten eingeladen und durften eine frisch zubereitete Mahlzeit mit dem eigenen Gemüse genießen – ein echtes&amp;nbsp;Highlight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Danach ging es zurück zum Hostel: von den gemeinschaftlichen Gärten zurück in das geschäftige, laute Miraflores. Dort konnte ich den letzten Tag der &lt;em&gt;Semana del Café&lt;/em&gt; vollends genießen. Zwischen dem warmen Kaffeeduft und der wuselnden Menschenmenge lernte ich einige interessante Menschen kennen, unter anderem einen Tattoo-Künstler, der gerade dabei war, Besucherinnen und Besuchern temporäre Tattoos zum Thema Kaffee zu malen. Theo und ich waren willkommene Gesprächspartner, denn wir unterhielten uns eine ganze Weile über sein Leben und seine Arbeit in Peru – eine kleine Pause für ihn im Trubel des&amp;nbsp;Marktes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Im Laufe des Abends tauschte ich außerdem Kontakte mit einigen Standbesitzerinnen aus, bei denen ich Pullis, eine Bauchtasche und eine neue Hose ergatterte. Denn eines wurde mir in diesen Tagen sehr deutlich: Beim Packen für das Jahr hatte ich nicht die besten Entscheidungen&amp;nbsp;getroffen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ich hatte lange eine Packliste geführt und am Ende auch eine, die alles enthielt, was ich tatsächlich brauchte. Doch kurz vor der Abreise begann ich plötzlich, diese Liste mit mir selbst zu verhandeln – mit überraschend schlechten Argumenten. Pullis? Brauche ich nicht so viele. Spiele? Mit wem soll ich in einem kleinen Dorf spielen? Kleidung für kalte Wanderungen? In Peru werde ich das bestimmt nicht machen. Tja – da habe ich mich gewaltig vertan und musste nun kreative Notlösungen&amp;nbsp;finden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Tríunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240631_DxO_xJ4J3gVrZ.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of a banana Tree" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240629_DxO_tmrYuPpMN.jpg"&gt;&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Zum ersten mal gesehen: Ein&amp;nbsp;Bananenbaum&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Tríunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240636_DxO_pZkmJkSXxO.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Tríunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240638_DxO_gi_7-5bmx.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Tríunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240642_DxO_xBG7qJlfa.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Montag, 25. August&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heute hätten wir uns mit einer Mitarbeiterin der deutschen Botschaft treffen sollen, die uns weitere Informationen über das Land und unseren Freiwilligenausweis geben wollte. In Peru benötigt man vielerorts eine Identifikationsnummer, die sogenannte &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNI&lt;/span&gt;. Sie wird unter anderem für Yape (ein digitales Zahlungsmittel, vergleichbar mit PayPal) genutzt, aber auch in Hostels oder bei größeren Anschaffungen&amp;nbsp;verlangt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Das Treffen fand jedoch nicht statt, da die Mitarbeiterin kurzfristig erkrankt war. Glück im Unglück: Mit der gewonnenen Zeit konnten wir uns &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SIM&lt;/span&gt;-Karten besorgen und waren endlich wieder mit der Außenwelt verbunden. Wir waren unabhängiger und konnten uns nun freier in der Stadt&amp;nbsp;bewegen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wir fuhren mit dem Bus in die Altstadt Limas. Wer sich über überfüllte U-Bahnen oder Busse in Deutschland beschwert, wird in den Bussen Limas nicht einmal einsteigen können. Sie waren so voll, dass man sich mehr biegen und quetschen musste, als man es je in einer Runde Twister getan hat. Auch das Aussteigen war eine eigene Erfahrung und bestand im Wesentlichen aus den Worten „¡Bajo!“ und&amp;nbsp;„Pásame“.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Die Altstadt selbst beeindruckte mich sehr. Die Gebäude stammen größtenteils aus der Zeit der spanischen Kolonialherrschaft, die 1535 begann. Lima wurde als „Stadt der Könige“ gegründet und diente lange als Hauptsitz des Vizekönigs von Peru – eines der wichtigsten politischen und wirtschaftlichen Zentren des spanischen Reiches in Südamerika. Kirche, Verwaltung und wohlhabende Kolonialherren investierten in prunkvolle Kirchen, imposante Paläste und kunstvoll gestaltete Wohnhäuser. Lokale Materialien wie Ziegel, Holz und Stein wurden dabei aufwendig verarbeitet. All das spiegelte sich deutlich bei unserem Besuch dieses &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UNESCO&lt;/span&gt;-Weltkulturerbes&amp;nbsp;wider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Den Abend ließen wir im Parque de la Reserva ausklingen, wo wir zwischen Churros und Freizeitattraktionen eine beeindruckende Wassershow&amp;nbsp;bestaunten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250008_DxO_eZP13gl30.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250032_DxO_2TchPjv8a.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250045_DxO_mWZb9FTXF.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250052_DxO_1FiPlr7_e.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250099_DxO_y5kqsrqkm.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250124_DxO_6nd8-JWpU.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250154_DxO_XMbq0_BOW.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250172_DxO_qOFtIZhz_.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250213_DxO_Pl9ZYhu-a.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260224_DxO_clMn0PQo6.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260245_DxO_vUifIVnN9.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Dienstag, 26. August&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nach einem weiteren Meeting mit Doris besuchten wir heute den touristischen Stadtteil Barranco. Wir folgten der Strandpromenade und genossen den Blick auf den Pazifik, in dem ich – gemeinsam mit nur wenigen anderen – schwimmen war. Wegen der Kälte fuhren die Schwimmer:innen anschließend mit dem Taxi zurück zum Hostel. Den Abend verbrachten wir mit Empanadas, gefüllten Teigtaschen etwa mit Käse, Huhn oder Gemüse. Für mich ein guter Ersatz für den Döner, den man für ein Jahr lang nicht mehr genießen kann.Für den letzten Tag war nichts mehr geplant, da wir Lima zu unterschiedlichen Zeiten verließen und Doris bei allen Abreisen dabei sein wollte. Erik und ich trafen uns am Nachmittag noch mit David, dem Leiter von &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CACI&lt;/span&gt; Satinaki – dem Ort, an dem wir arbeiten und leben würden. Er erklärte uns vieles: von den Menschen vor Ort bis hin zu Reisemöglichkeiten während des&amp;nbsp;Jahres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Am Abend ging es für uns schließlich los. In Peru wird viel mit Fernbussen gereist, und der Komfort ist dabei deutlich höher als in Deutschland. Es gibt große Terminals mit Gepäckabgabe, und die Busse selbst sind erstaunlich bequem: breite Sitze, viel Beinfreiheit und Rückenlehnen, die sich bis zu 160 oder sogar 180 Grad verstellen lassen. Die elf Stunden Fahrt nach Pichanaki konnte man so durchaus&amp;nbsp;genießen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was dort geschah, folgt im nächsten&amp;nbsp;Post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rückblickend waren diese ersten Tage überwältigend, aber fantastisch. Sei es das Stadtleben, das Essen oder der starke Kontrast zwischen den verschiedenen Vierteln – langsam wurde mir klar, dass ich in einer mir fremden Kultur gelandet war und hier ein Jahr verbringen würde. Ein Jahr, auf das ich mich genau aus diesem Grund freue: wegen des kulturellen&amp;nbsp;Austauschs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bleibt&amp;nbsp;gespannt,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Buena semana y hasta la&amp;nbsp;próxima!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</ns0:content><ns0:category term="Peru" /></ns0:entry><ns0:entry><ns0:title>Enfin?!</ns0:title><ns0:link href="https://cyprieninperu.netlify.app/fr/going-abroad/?utm_source=atomfeed" rel="alternate" /><ns0:published>2025-10-10T09:00:00-05:00</ns0:published><ns0:updated>2025-10-10T09:00:00-05:00</ns0:updated><ns0:author><ns0:name>Cyprien Chevallier</ns0:name></ns0:author><ns0:id>tag:cyprieninperu.netlify.app,2025-10-10:/fr/going-abroad/</ns0:id><ns0:summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;J’ai enfin réussi à publier mon premier véritable article. J’y raconte mes premiers jours au Pérou, de mon arrivée à Lima jusqu’au voyage vers ma nouvelle maison, Miguel&amp;nbsp;Grau.&lt;/p&gt;</ns0:summary><ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bien que je sois au Pérou depuis plus de deux mois déjà, je n’avais encore réussi à publier aucun article – jusqu’à aujourd’hui. J’aimerais revenir sur ces quelques jours passés à Lima, qui ont servi de préparation à mon engagement à Miguel&amp;nbsp;Grau.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tout a commencé le vendredi 22 août. Le départ était prévu à 14 h 45 pour moi et les vingt autres volontaires : de Francfort à Lima, avec une escale à Bogotá. Épuisés, parfois malades à cause du voyage, et chargés de nos bagages en trois parties, nous sommes arrivés vers trois heures du matin à notre auberge de jeunesse, le &lt;em&gt;Flying Dog&lt;/em&gt;, à&amp;nbsp;Lima.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La première chose qui nous a fait rire fut l’agencement pour le moins inhabituel de la chambre. L’une des fenêtres donnait directement sur une plante d’aloe vera accrochée à un mur de briques. Le contact avec nos voisins de chambre – heureusement eux aussi volontaires – s’est fait très rapidement, notamment parce que le mur séparant les chambres ne montait pas jusqu’au plafond et qu’une fenêtre ouverte y avait été&amp;nbsp;aménagée.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Après seulement quelques heures de sommeil, notre programme a repris dès le dimanche matin. Nous avons rencontré Doris, notre référente nationale d’Ecoselva, qui allait nous accompagner tout au long de l’année. Nous avons passé plusieurs heures dans une salle de réunion, où elle nous a transmis de nombreuses informations sur l’année à venir et notre séjour à Lima. Bien que nous ayons déjà suivi un séminaire de préparation de dix jours avant le départ, cette rencontre s’est révélée très précieuse, notamment grâce aux nombreuses années d’expérience que Doris a partagées avec nous sur la vie au&amp;nbsp;Pérou.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dans l’après-midi, nous avons découvert Miraflores, l’un des quartiers les plus aisés de Lima. Très orienté vers le tourisme, c’est également là que se trouvait notre auberge. C’est ici que j’ai vu l’océan Pacifique pour la première fois – et où j’ai malheureusement trempé ma première, et plus belle, des quatre pantalons que j’avais emportés… dans l’eau&amp;nbsp;salée.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nous avons également exploré les alentours de l’auberge : un petit bar servant un excellent pisco sour, plusieurs grands espaces verts peuplés de chats errants que l’on pouvait caresser (et, en théorie, même adopter), ainsi que le marché du café &lt;em&gt;Semana del Café&lt;/em&gt;, qui se tenait sur plusieurs&amp;nbsp;jours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pendant ces journées de préparation, Ecoselva prenait en charge notre restauration. Nous déjeunions dans un restaurant arabe et dînions dans un restaurant chinois. Ce dernier n’a malheureusement pas convaincu grand monde. Avec le recul, je suis sûr que nous nous en accommoderions bien mieux aujourd’hui. Ce n’était finalement pas tant une question de goût que d’adaptation : nos corps et nos attentes n’étaient tout simplement pas encore arrivés au&amp;nbsp;Pérou.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;À cela s’est ajouté le fait que j’avais proposé de commander une boisson à l’aloe vera, afin de goûter à tout ce qui nous était proposé. Mais cette boisson n’a pas vraiment séduit nos palais à ce moment-là, et le restaurant s’est ainsi forgé une réputation un peu mitigée au sein du groupe – sans doute aussi parce que tout cela nous est arrivé de manière très&amp;nbsp;inattendue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of the Pacific in Lima" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230536_DxO_HipNVxR4H.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of a metal pole with a sticker and the Pacific in the background" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230540_DxO_x4EQ_uVjc.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of a road and some buildings in Lima" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230556_DxO_Ldnar9w-0I.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="The Pacific behind a beton bridge" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230559_DxO_uBmd7MWe1.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Waves of the Pacific hitting Stones" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230600_DxO_eGgQayloN.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Dimanche 24 août&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loin du regard vigilant des agents de sécurité et des balais des équipes de nettoyage, nous avons découvert aujourd’hui une autre facette de Lima : une métropole de près de onze millions d’habitants, marquée par de forts contrastes&amp;nbsp;sociaux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nous nous sommes rendus dans le quartier de Villa María del Triunfo, un &lt;em&gt;pueblo joven&lt;/em&gt; – un quartier structurellement défavorisé, principalement habité par des migrant·e·s originaires des Andes et souvent né de l’initiative de ses propres habitants. Le trajet fut pour le moins mouvementé : au Pérou, le code de la route ressemble davantage à une suggestion, la ceinture de sécurité est souvent décorative, et le klaxon est utilisé bien plus fréquemment que le frein. Pour nous, nouveaux arrivants d’Allemagne, cela paraissait chaotique au premier abord, mais cela fait tout simplement partie du quotidien&amp;nbsp;ici.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sur place, on nous a présenté un projet d’agriculture urbaine. Il y a environ quinze ans, quelques femmes ont décidé de rendre leur environnement plus agréable à vivre. Comme toute construction est interdite sous les lignes à haute tension, elles ont obtenu l’autorisation d’y cultiver des fruits et des légumes. Les débuts ont été difficiles, peu de personnes croyant réellement au projet. Pour pouvoir commencer, elles ont construit une clôture de fortune, faite de pneus, de planches en bois et de tôles ondulées, afin de protéger les&amp;nbsp;cultures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aujourd’hui, le projet s’est étendu à plusieurs quartiers et rassemble de nombreuses familles qui cultivent de petites parcelles. Certaines vendent leur production, d’autres cultivent uniquement pour leurs propres besoins. Ce qui les unit toutes, c’est le soin et l’amour apportés à leurs jardins. À l’heure du déjeuner, nous avons été invités dans un autre jardin du projet pour partager un repas fraîchement préparé à partir des légumes cultivés sur place – un moment fort de la&amp;nbsp;journée.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nous sommes ensuite retournés à l’auberge : des jardins communautaires au Miraflores animé et bruyant. J’y ai pleinement profité du dernier jour de la &lt;em&gt;Semana del Café&lt;/em&gt;. Entre l’odeur chaleureuse du café et la foule en mouvement, j’ai fait la connaissance de personnes très intéressantes, notamment un tatoueur qui dessinait des tatouages temporaires sur le thème du café. Theo et moi étions des interlocuteurs bienvenus : nous avons longuement discuté avec lui de sa vie et de son travail au Pérou, lui offrant ainsi une petite pause au milieu de l’agitation du&amp;nbsp;marché.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dans la soirée, j’ai également échangé mes coordonnées avec quelques exposantes, auprès desquelles j’ai acheté des pulls, une banane et un nouveau pantalon. Une chose est alors devenue très claire pour moi : lors de la préparation de mon sac pour l’année, je n’avais pas toujours fait les meilleurs&amp;nbsp;choix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;J’avais pourtant tenu une liste détaillée, qui contenait tout ce dont j’avais réellement besoin. Mais peu avant le départ, j’ai commencé à négocier cette liste avec moi-même – avec des arguments étonnamment mauvais. Des pulls ? Pas besoin d’en prendre autant. Des jeux ? Avec qui jouerais-je dans un petit village ? Des vêtements chauds pour la randonnée ? Je ne ferai sûrement pas ça au Pérou. Eh bien… je me suis lourdement trompé et j’ai dû trouver des solutions de&amp;nbsp;fortune.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Tríunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240631_DxO_xJ4J3gVrZ.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of a banana Tree" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240629_DxO_tmrYuPpMN.jpg"&gt;&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Première fois que je voyais un&amp;nbsp;bananier&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Tríunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240636_DxO_pZkmJkSXxO.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Tríunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240638_DxO_gi_7-5bmx.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Tríunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240642_DxO_xBG7qJlfa.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Lundi 25 août&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nous devions aujourd’hui rencontrer une représentante de l’ambassade d’Allemagne, qui devait nous fournir davantage d’informations sur le pays et sur notre carte de volontaire. Au Pérou, une grande partie des démarches nécessite un numéro d’identification, appelé &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Il est utilisé notamment pour Yape – un moyen de paiement numérique comparable à PayPal – mais aussi dans les auberges ou lors d’achats plus&amp;nbsp;importants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La rencontre a finalement été annulée, la représentante étant tombée malade à court terme. Un mal pour un bien : le temps gagné nous a permis d’acheter des cartes &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SIM&lt;/span&gt; et de nous reconnecter enfin au monde extérieur. Nous étions désormais plus autonomes et pouvions nous déplacer plus librement dans la&amp;nbsp;ville.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nous avons pris le bus pour rejoindre le centre historique de Lima. Ceux qui se plaignent des métros ou bus bondés en Allemagne ne pourraient même pas monter dans les bus liméniens. Ils étaient si pleins qu’il fallait se contorsionner plus que lors d’une partie de Twister. La descente du bus était elle aussi toute une expérience, se résumant le plus souvent aux mots « ¡Bajo! » et « Pásame&amp;nbsp;».&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le centre historique m’a profondément impressionné. La majorité des bâtiments datent de la période de la colonisation espagnole, qui débuta en 1535. Lima, fondée sous le nom de « Cité des Rois », fut longtemps le siège du vice-roi du Pérou, l’un des centres politiques et économiques majeurs de l’empire espagnol en Amérique du Sud. L’Église, l’administration et les élites coloniales ont investi dans des églises somptueuses, des palais imposants et des demeures richement décorées, utilisant des matériaux locaux comme la brique, le bois et la pierre. Tout cela se ressent fortement lors de la visite de ce site classé au patrimoine mondial de l’&lt;span class="caps"&gt;UNESCO&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nous avons terminé la journée au &lt;em&gt;Parque de la Reserva&lt;/em&gt;, où nous avons assisté à un impressionnant spectacle de fontaines, entre churros et attractions de&amp;nbsp;loisirs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250008_DxO_eZP13gl30.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250032_DxO_2TchPjv8a.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250045_DxO_mWZb9FTXF.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250052_DxO_1FiPlr7_e.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250099_DxO_y5kqsrqkm.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250124_DxO_6nd8-JWpU.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250154_DxO_XMbq0_BOW.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250172_DxO_qOFtIZhz_.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250213_DxO_Pl9ZYhu-a.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260224_DxO_clMn0PQo6.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260245_DxO_vUifIVnN9.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Mardi 26 août&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Après une nouvelle réunion avec Doris, nous avons visité aujourd’hui le quartier touristique de Barranco. Nous avons longé la promenade côtière et profité de la vue sur le Pacifique, dans lequel je me suis baigné avec seulement quelques autres courageux. À cause du froid, les nageurs sont rentrés à l’auberge en taxi. Le soir, nous avons mangé des empanadas, des chaussons de pâte farcis au fromage, au poulet ou aux légumes – pour moi, un bon substitut au kebab dont il faudra se passer pendant un&amp;nbsp;an.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour le dernier jour, rien n’était prévu, car chacun quittait Lima à des horaires différents et Doris souhaitait être présente pour chaque départ. Erik et moi avons rencontré dans l’après-midi David, le responsable de &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CACI&lt;/span&gt; Satinaki, l’endroit où nous allions travailler et vivre. Il nous a expliqué de nombreuses choses, des personnes sur place aux possibilités de voyage pendant&amp;nbsp;l’année.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le soir même, nous avons pris la route. Au Pérou, les trajets longue distance se font principalement en bus, avec un confort nettement supérieur à celui auquel on est habitué en Allemagne. Les terminaux disposent de consignes à bagages, et les bus eux-mêmes sont remarquablement confortables : sièges larges, beaucoup d’espace pour les jambes et dossiers inclinables jusqu’à 160, voire 180 degrés. Les onze heures de trajet jusqu’à Pichanaki se sont donc révélées plutôt&amp;nbsp;agréables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La suite de l’aventure fera l’objet du prochain&amp;nbsp;article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avec le recul, ces premiers jours ont été à la fois bouleversants et magnifiques. Qu’il s’agisse de la vie urbaine, de la nourriture ou des contrastes saisissants entre les quartiers, j’ai peu à peu réalisé que je me trouvais dans une culture qui m’était étrangère et que j’allais y vivre pendant un an. Une année que j’attends avec impatience, précisément pour cette raison : l’échange&amp;nbsp;culturel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Restez à l’écoute,
Buena semana y hasta la próxima&amp;nbsp;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</ns0:content><ns0:category term="peru" /></ns0:entry></ns0:feed>