<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ns0:feed xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><ns0:title>Cyprien in Peru - peru</ns0:title><ns0:link href="https://devccypri3n1563.netlify.app/" rel="alternate" /><ns0:link href="https://devccypri3n1563.netlify.app/feeds/peru.atom.xml" rel="self" /><ns0:id>https://devccypri3n1563.netlify.app/</ns0:id><ns0:updated>2025-11-29T00:00:00-05:00</ns0:updated><ns0:entry><ns0:title>11 hours later…</ns0:title><ns0:link href="https://devccypri3n1563.netlify.app/11-hours-later/?utm_source=atomfeed" rel="alternate" /><ns0:published>2025-11-29T00:00:00-05:00</ns0:published><ns0:updated>2025-11-29T00:00:00-05:00</ns0:updated><ns0:author><ns0:name>Cyprien Chevallier</ns0:name></ns0:author><ns0:id>tag:devccypri3n1563.netlify.app,2025-11-29:/11-hours-later/</ns0:id><ns0:summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Arrival in Miguel Grau, discovering our rooms and the village square. In this article, I tell you about the end of our bus journey and our first days in the&amp;nbsp;village.&lt;/p&gt;</ns0:summary><ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;… we finally arrived at the Movílbus terminal in Pichanaki. It was around 7 in the morning, but the city of 20,000 inhabitants had long been awake. All kinds of vehicles—mototaxis, pick-up trucks, and small lorries—zipped along the multilane main road. The air was filled with swirling dust and the acrid exhaust of the traffic. Tired but excited, Erik and I waited for Aurelia, with whom I’d been coordinating our&amp;nbsp;arrival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the outside, the terminal looked like a garage, but inside it had a few rows of seats and a small counter. About an hour later, a dark grey pick-up truck arrived, with Aurelia and a few others inside. So here they were—the team we were going to live and work with for an entire&amp;nbsp;year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elvis, in his forties, describes himself as a happy man: “As long as there’s beer, coffee, and women.” A rock-’n’-roll fan who’s rarely seen without his&amp;nbsp;motorcycle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aurelia, head of the quality-control lab, Q-Grader for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CACI&lt;/span&gt; Satinaki for the past eight years, and mother to Mavi. She always has the lab’s best coffee and best&amp;nbsp;chocolate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blanca, our host mother for the year, who feeds us with her cooking and helps us settle into her&amp;nbsp;home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mavi, part-time princess, who brings joy and sunshine to the lab every&amp;nbsp;day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We enjoyed a wonderful breakfast and chatted together. The food was delicious: bread, eggs, and yuca, a root vegetable with a potato-like flavor. Fried yuca is even better—crispy on the outside, soft on the inside. A real&amp;nbsp;treat!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About an hour later, we were already on the road to Yurinaki. During the drive, we made a brief stop by the roadside, where a small wooden hut with a leaf roof was selling coconuts “to go.” Apart from Erik and me, no one seemed surprised by this improvised drive-through. After another hour on the road and a brand-new drink in hand, we reached Yurinaki, the closest town to Miguel Grau. Without much explanation—a cultural habit I’d soon have to get used to—we made a short stop there. Erik and I took the chance to explore the surroundings a bit, without straying too far into this still-unknown&amp;nbsp;territory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The town of about 1,500 inhabitants has at its center a beautiful green park with a stone stage in the middle. A road circles around it, lined with small shops and&amp;nbsp;restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later4_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432200069"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then left Yurinaki on a small road leading into the mountains. Far from the dense traffic of the cities, the air was pleasant: the sun warmed our skin, birds chirped in the trees, and a light breeze brushed our faces through the open windows. After about forty minutes of driving—punctuated by anecdotes and incredible views—we arrived at Blanca’s house. It’s an old stone house with a corrugated-metal roof. Several wooden structures scattered around shelter chickens, geese, and friends—plus an old Jeep and a workshop full of&amp;nbsp;tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of us would stay in the only room on the first floor, while the other would stay in David’s newer, more modern house. This second house, only a few minutes away, looks a lot like a European home, with a large terrace and several rooms with private bathrooms on the upper&amp;nbsp;floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I was supposed to sleep in the newer house, we had to swap rooms quickly because of Erik’s allergies. I have to admit that this change was tough for me at first. For those who know me: I’m not exactly a fan of insects. And this “new” room had practically no insulation—no glass window, just a plastic tarp for a ceiling. I quickly came into contact with all sorts of insects: a wasp stung me right in the chest, mosquitoes swarmed around my bed, and so on. Fortunately, I soon got a mosquito net and began to slowly (very slowly) get used to these little creatures. Ah, and the chickens? Unforgettable—especially their 3-a.m. alarm clock&amp;nbsp;routine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Arrival in Miguel Grau" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later13_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432252461"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Davids Haus" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later2_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432254148"&gt;&lt;p class="caption"&gt;David’s&amp;nbsp;house&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="3/5 Katzen von Blanca" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later7_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432233749"&gt;&lt;p class="caption"&gt;3 of Blanca’s 5&amp;nbsp;cats&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Hühner und Gänse" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later3_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432261528"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later0_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432256028"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, these first days were fantastic: discovering the lab, our work, meeting new friends, and getting our first introduction to Peruvian cuisine—which I’ll write more about in a separate article. The immersion is complete, and it’s genuinely fascinating to discover this new culture, one I knew nothing about before. I’ll let the next photos speak for&amp;nbsp;themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;¡Buenos días y hasta la&amp;nbsp;próxima!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyprien&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later15_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432239540"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later11_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432216274"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later14_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432232078"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later16_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432244024"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later12_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432257686"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later8_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432201490"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;</ns0:content><ns0:category term="peru" /></ns0:entry><ns0:entry><ns0:title>Finally?!</ns0:title><ns0:link href="https://devccypri3n1563.netlify.app/going-abroad/?utm_source=atomfeed" rel="alternate" /><ns0:published>2025-10-27T09:00:00-05:00</ns0:published><ns0:updated>2025-10-27T09:00:00-05:00</ns0:updated><ns0:author><ns0:name>Cyprien Chevallier</ns0:name></ns0:author><ns0:id>tag:devccypri3n1563.netlify.app,2025-10-27:/going-abroad/</ns0:id><ns0:summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I finally got around to publishing my first real article. I describe my first day in Peru, up until my journey towards my new home, Miguel&amp;nbsp;Grau.&lt;/p&gt;</ns0:summary><ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Although I’ve been in Peru for more than three weeks—well, almost two months—I hadn’t posted anything yet… until today! So let me tell you about those first few days in Lima, which served as preparation for my placement in Miguel&amp;nbsp;Grau.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything began on Friday, August 22. That day, the other volunteers and I boarded our flight to Lima, with a layover in Bogotá. Exhausted, a bit out of sorts, and loaded down with my three pieces of luggage, we finally arrived at our hostel at 3 a.m. The Flying Dog immediately gave me a taste of what I had signed up for. Our room, for example, looked out onto an aloe vera plant hanging on a brick wall. We also got along pretty easily with our neighbors (luckily, they were volunteers too), because the wall didn’t reach the ceiling and one window stayed permanently open. A bit farther down the hallway, I discovered Peruvian bathrooms for the first time: toilet paper strictly forbidden, unless you want to clog the pipes! The bathroom, home to a few spiders and insects acting as “pets,” at least had hot water… Looking back, none of this was actually so bad—you just have to&amp;nbsp;adapt!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Saturday, August 23,&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few hours of sleep, we started the day with a light breakfast and a meeting with Doris, our local Ecoselva mentor who will accompany us throughout the&amp;nbsp;year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon, we explored Miraflores, one of Lima’s wealthiest and most touristy districts—which also happened to be where our hostel was—and we visited the Pacific Ocean, where I unfortunately soaked the first of the four pairs of pants I had&amp;nbsp;brought…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also checked out the area around the hostel: a really nice bar with excellent Pisco Sours, big green parks filled with stray cats to pet or adopt, and a multi-day coffee market with tons of fascinating stands. Meals were taken care of by Ecoselva: lunch at an Arab restaurant, dinner at a Chinese one. The latter didn’t win many hearts— not only was the food pretty mediocre, but out of misguided curiosity, I ordered an aloe-vera drink. Imagine buying aloe-vera shampoo at the grocery store, then mixing in chunks of fruit yogurt—that’s exactly what it tasted like for me and 90% of the volunteers. But I shouldn’t complain: if our year were made only of perfect experiences, we’d be bored stiff—and I wouldn’t have absurd stories to tell. Like the scooter that suddenly drove into the restaurant during&amp;nbsp;dinner…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of the Pacific in Lima" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230536_DxO_HipNVxR4H.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of a metal pole with a sticker and the Pacific in the background" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230540_DxO_x4EQ_uVjc.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of a road and some buildings in Lima" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230556_DxO_Ldnar9w-0I.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="The Pacific behind a beton bridge" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230559_DxO_uBmd7MWe1.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Waves of the Pacific hitting Stones" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230600_DxO_eGgQayloN.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Sunday, August 24,&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Away from police patrols and cleaning crews, we discovered a very different side of the city. Lima, a metropolis of 11 million people, is marked by stark contrasts between wealth and poverty. We visited Villa María del Triunfo, a pueblo joven—a low-income neighborhood mainly inhabited by migrants from the Andes. The ride there was quite an experience: traffic laws are more like suggestions, seatbelts are optional accessories, and drivers use the horn more often than the&amp;nbsp;brakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once there, we were introduced to an urban-agriculture project. About fifteen years ago, a group of women decided to beautify the local landscape. Since construction is prohibited under electrical pylons, they secured permission to grow fruits and vegetables there. The beginning was tough—few people believed in the project. To protect the crops from thieves, the women built a makeshift fence out of tires, planks, and corrugated metal&amp;nbsp;sheets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, the project has expanded to other districts and now includes many families cultivating small plots. Some sell their produce, others grow food for their own use. All the gardens are arranged with a lot of love. At noon, we were invited to another garden in the project to enjoy a meal prepared with their fresh vegetables—absolutely delicious! Then we headed back to the hostel through Lima’s chaotic&amp;nbsp;traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent the rest of the day at the last session of Semana del Café, hidden among clouds of warm coffee aromas and the lively crowds. I met some interesting people, including a tattoo artist drawing temporary coffee-themed tattoos. Theo and I chatted with him about his life and work in Peru—giving him a much-needed break. Later, I exchanged contacts with several vendors from whom I bought sweaters, a fanny pack, and a new pair of pants. Because I have to admit: I packed terribly. Despite making a careful list and preparing everything meticulously, I forgot the most essential thing—myself. I left behind clothes, games, and other important and useful things in Germany. And what I did bring—like pants and t-shirts—isn’t nearly enough. As my best friend would say: “Life is hard.” I can’t change it now, so I’ve accepted it and&amp;nbsp;adapted!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Tríunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240631_DxO_xJ4J3gVrZ.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of a banana Tree" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240629_DxO_tmrYuPpMN.jpg"&gt;&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Zum ersten mal gesehen: Ein&amp;nbsp;Bananenbaum&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Tríunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240636_DxO_pZkmJkSXxO.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Tríunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240638_DxO_gi_7-5bmx.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Tríunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240642_DxO_xBG7qJlfa.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Monday, August 25,&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were supposed to meet with a woman from the German embassy to get information about the country and our volunteer &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ID&lt;/span&gt; card. In Peru, you often need a number called the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CNI&lt;/span&gt; (código único de identificación), which appears on the card. It’s essential for using Yape (a digital payment service, similar to PayPal, accepted almost everywhere), but also for hostels and big purchases. Unfortunately, the meeting didn’t happen because she was sick. Honestly, that worked out well—we finally had time to buy &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SIM&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We took the bus to Lima’s historic center. Anyone who complains about the crowded public transportation in Germany wouldn’t even be able to step inside a Lima bus. They were so packed that we had to twist ourselves more than in a game of Twister. Getting off was just as entertaining: you simply shout “¡Bajo!” and&amp;nbsp;“¡Pásame!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to the historic center: the impressive buildings date back to the Spanish colonial period, which began in 1535. When Lima was founded as the “City of Kings,” it became the seat of the Viceroyalty of Peru—one of the most important political and economic hubs of the Spanish Empire in South America. Wealthy settlers, the Church, and the colonial administration invested heavily in lavish churches, grand palaces, and well-preserved houses to display their power and wealth. Local materials such as brick, wood, and stone were crafted with great skill. We saw all of this during our visit to this &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UNESCO&lt;/span&gt; World Heritage Site. The historic center felt like a step back in time, with the beautifully preserved Plaza Mayor and our tour of the San Francisco monastery. While wandering through the streets, I also noticed how the urban landscape shifted: between the skyscrapers and modern buildings, a few historic structures remained—often now used by government&amp;nbsp;offices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ended the evening at the Parque de la Reserva, watching a water show while snacking on&amp;nbsp;churros.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250008_DxO_eZP13gl30.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250032_DxO_2TchPjv8a.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250045_DxO_mWZb9FTXF.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250052_DxO_1FiPlr7_e.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250099_DxO_y5kqsrqkm.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250124_DxO_6nd8-JWpU.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250154_DxO_XMbq0_BOW.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250172_DxO_qOFtIZhz_.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250213_DxO_Pl9ZYhu-a.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260224_DxO_clMn0PQo6.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260245_DxO_vUifIVnN9.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Tuesday, August 26,&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After another meeting with Doris, we headed to the tourist district of Barranco. We strolled along the seaside promenade and enjoyed the Pacific—where only a handful of brave souls (including me) dared to swim. Because it was so cold, the swimmers took a taxi back to the hostel. After some fresh empanadas, Jannes, Theo, and I ended the night with a Pizza Hut&amp;nbsp;dinner!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="A view of the Pacific" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260493_DxO_oWrPud-bS.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="A view of the Pacific with Limas skyscrapers and a Peruvian Flag" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260495_DxO_8yFdvy_U4.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cactuses with the Pacific in the Background" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260499_DxO_P4ImBAGCG7.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="A Closeup of a cactuses fruit" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260501_DxO_SkkT5tW59.jpg"&gt;&lt;p class="caption"&gt;The fruit found on the cactuses from the previous&amp;nbsp;photo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="A street in Lima leading to the Pacific in the background" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260504_DxO_GP6JGc0Tz.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="A pigeon flying over the waves of the pacific" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260510_DxO_3mTrgnlvv.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="A seagull flying over the pacific with the cityscape of Lima in the background" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260517_DxO_k_0ZP86hL.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Wednesday, August 27,&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we were all leaving Lima at different times and Doris wanted to be around, nothing official was planned for our last day. Erik and I had an afternoon meeting with David, the director of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CACI&lt;/span&gt; Satinaki, where we’ll work and live for the year. He explained a lot: who we’d be living and working with, details about traveling in the region, and&amp;nbsp;more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That evening, we left. In Peru, people often travel long-distance by bus, and the comfort level is far better than in Germany. There are large terminals for the different companies, complete with luggage check-in, and the buses are fantastic: wide, comfortable seats that recline 160 or even 180 degrees. So the ride to Pichanaki was looking pretty good! What happened 11 hours later will be the subject of the next&amp;nbsp;article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay&amp;nbsp;tuned,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buena semana y hasta la&amp;nbsp;próxima!&lt;/p&gt;</ns0:content><ns0:category term="peru" /></ns0:entry><ns0:entry><ns0:title>Let the journey begin: A year in Peru</ns0:title><ns0:link href="https://devccypri3n1563.netlify.app/the-adventure-begins/?utm_source=atomfeed" rel="alternate" /><ns0:published>2025-06-09T09:00:00-05:00</ns0:published><ns0:updated>2025-06-09T09:00:00-05:00</ns0:updated><ns0:author><ns0:name>Cyprien Chevallier</ns0:name></ns0:author><ns0:id>tag:devccypri3n1563.netlify.app,2025-06-09:/the-adventure-begins/</ns0:id><ns0:summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;May I present myself? Cyprien, 18 years old and on the way to&amp;nbsp;peru.&lt;/p&gt;</ns0:summary><ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Cyprien, and I&amp;#8217;m the person behind this&amp;nbsp;blog. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m doing a voluntary social year (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;FSJ&lt;/span&gt;) with the association &lt;a href="https://ecoselva.org"&gt;Ecoselva&lt;/a&gt; in Miguel Grau, a very small village in the heart of the Peruvian mountain rainforest. In this blog, I want to share my experiences, insights, and travels from this fantastic&amp;nbsp;year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for more posts—I can&amp;#8217;t wait to share my adventures&amp;nbsp;here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best&amp;nbsp;regards,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyprien&lt;/p&gt;</ns0:content><ns0:category term="Peru" /></ns0:entry></ns0:feed>