<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ns0:feed xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><ns0:title>Cyprien in Peru - peru</ns0:title><ns0:link href="https://cyprieninperu.netlify.app/" rel="alternate" /><ns0:link href="https://cyprieninperu.netlify.app/feeds/peru.atom.xml" rel="self" /><ns0:id>https://cyprieninperu.netlify.app/</ns0:id><ns0:updated>2025-11-29T00:00:00-05:00</ns0:updated><ns0:entry><ns0:title>11 hours later…</ns0:title><ns0:link href="https://cyprieninperu.netlify.app/11-hours-later/?utm_source=atomfeed" rel="alternate" /><ns0:published>2025-11-29T00:00:00-05:00</ns0:published><ns0:updated>2025-11-29T00:00:00-05:00</ns0:updated><ns0:author><ns0:name>Cyprien Chevallier</ns0:name></ns0:author><ns0:id>tag:cyprieninperu.netlify.app,2025-11-29:/11-hours-later/</ns0:id><ns0:summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Arrival in Miguel Grau, discovering our rooms and the village square. In this article, I tell you about the end of our bus journey and our first days in the&amp;nbsp;village.&lt;/p&gt;</ns0:summary><ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;… we finally arrived at the Movílbus terminal in Pichanaki. It was around 7 in the morning, but the city of 20,000 inhabitants had long been awake. All kinds of vehicles—mototaxis, pick-up trucks, and small lorries—zipped along the multilane main road. The air was filled with swirling dust and the acrid exhaust of the traffic. Tired but excited, Erik and I waited for Aurelia, with whom I’d been coordinating our&amp;nbsp;arrival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the outside, the terminal looked like a garage, but inside it had a few rows of seats and a small counter. About an hour later, a dark grey pick-up truck arrived, with Aurelia and a few others inside. So here they were—the team we were going to live and work with for an entire&amp;nbsp;year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elvis, in his forties, describes himself as a happy man: “As long as there’s beer, coffee, and women.” A rock-’n’-roll fan who’s rarely seen without his&amp;nbsp;motorcycle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aurelia, head of the quality-control lab, Q-Grader for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CACI&lt;/span&gt; Satinaki for the past eight years, and mother to Mavi. She always has the lab’s best coffee and best&amp;nbsp;chocolate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blanca, our host mother for the year, who feeds us with her cooking and helps us settle into her&amp;nbsp;home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mavi, part-time princess, who brings joy and sunshine to the lab every&amp;nbsp;day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We enjoyed a wonderful breakfast and chatted together. The food was delicious: bread, eggs, and yuca, a root vegetable with a potato-like flavor. Fried yuca is even better—crispy on the outside, soft on the inside. A real&amp;nbsp;treat!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About an hour later, we were already on the road to Yurinaki. During the drive, we made a brief stop by the roadside, where a small wooden hut with a leaf roof was selling coconuts “to go.” Apart from Erik and me, no one seemed surprised by this improvised drive-through. After another hour on the road and a brand-new drink in hand, we reached Yurinaki, the closest town to Miguel Grau. Without much explanation—a cultural habit I’d soon have to get used to—we made a short stop there. Erik and I took the chance to explore the surroundings a bit, without straying too far into this still-unknown&amp;nbsp;territory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The town of about 1,500 inhabitants has at its center a beautiful green park with a stone stage in the middle. A road circles around it, lined with small shops and&amp;nbsp;restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later4_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432200069"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then left Yurinaki on a small road leading into the mountains. Far from the dense traffic of the cities, the air was pleasant: the sun warmed our skin, birds chirped in the trees, and a light breeze brushed our faces through the open windows. After about forty minutes of driving—punctuated by anecdotes and incredible views—we arrived at Blanca’s house. It’s an old stone house with a corrugated-metal roof. Several wooden structures scattered around shelter chickens, geese, and friends—plus an old Jeep and a workshop full of&amp;nbsp;tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of us would stay in the only room on the first floor, while the other would stay in David’s newer, more modern house. This second house, only a few minutes away, looks a lot like a European home, with a large terrace and several rooms with private bathrooms on the upper&amp;nbsp;floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I was supposed to sleep in the newer house, we had to swap rooms quickly because of Erik’s allergies. I have to admit that this change was tough for me at first. For those who know me: I’m not exactly a fan of insects. And this “new” room had practically no insulation—no glass window, just a plastic tarp for a ceiling. I quickly came into contact with all sorts of insects: a wasp stung me right in the chest, mosquitoes swarmed around my bed, and so on. Fortunately, I soon got a mosquito net and began to slowly (very slowly) get used to these little creatures. Ah, and the chickens? Unforgettable—especially their 3-a.m. alarm clock&amp;nbsp;routine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Arrival in Miguel Grau" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later13_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432252461"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Davids Haus" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later2_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432254148"&gt;&lt;p class="caption"&gt;David’s&amp;nbsp;house&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="3/5 Katzen von Blanca" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later7_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432233749"&gt;&lt;p class="caption"&gt;3 of Blanca’s 5&amp;nbsp;cats&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Hühner und Gänse" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later3_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432261528"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later0_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432256028"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, these first days were fantastic: discovering the lab, our work, meeting new friends, and getting our first introduction to Peruvian cuisine—which I’ll write more about in a separate article. The immersion is complete, and it’s genuinely fascinating to discover this new culture, one I knew nothing about before. I’ll let the next photos speak for&amp;nbsp;themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;¡Buenos días y hasta la&amp;nbsp;próxima!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyprien&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later15_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432239540"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later11_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432216274"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later14_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432232078"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later16_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432244024"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later12_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432257686"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/11-hours-later8_converted.webp?updatedAt=1764432201490"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;</ns0:content><ns0:category term="peru" /></ns0:entry><ns0:entry><ns0:title>Finally?!</ns0:title><ns0:link href="https://cyprieninperu.netlify.app/going-abroad/?utm_source=atomfeed" rel="alternate" /><ns0:published>2025-10-27T09:00:00-05:00</ns0:published><ns0:updated>2025-10-27T09:00:00-05:00</ns0:updated><ns0:author><ns0:name>Cyprien Chevallier</ns0:name></ns0:author><ns0:id>tag:cyprieninperu.netlify.app,2025-10-27:/going-abroad/</ns0:id><ns0:summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve finally managed to publish my first proper article. In it, I describe my first days in Peru, from arriving in Lima to traveling to my new home in Miguel&amp;nbsp;Grau.&lt;/p&gt;</ns0:summary><ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Although I have now been in Peru for more than two months, I haven’t managed to publish a single article so far – until now. Today, I’d like to look back on the few days we spent in Lima, which served as preparation for my placement in Miguel&amp;nbsp;Grau.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything began on Friday, August 22. The departure for the twenty other volunteers and me was scheduled for 2:45 p.m., flying from Frankfurt to Lima via Bogotá. Exhausted, occasionally travel-sick, and burdened with my three-piece luggage, we arrived at around three in the morning at our hostel in Lima, the &lt;em&gt;Flying Dog&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing that made us laugh was the room layout, which still felt completely absurd to us at that point. One of the windows, for example, looked straight onto an aloe vera plant hanging against a brick wall. We quickly got in touch with our neighbors—fortunately also volunteers—since the wall between the rooms didn’t reach the ceiling and even had an open window built into&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After only a few hours of sleep, our schedule resumed on Sunday morning. We met Doris, our national coordinator from Ecoselva, who would be accompanying us throughout the year. We spent several hours in a meeting room, where she shared a wide range of information about the year ahead and our stay in Lima. Although we had already completed a ten-day preparation seminar before departure, this meeting proved extremely helpful—especially because Doris shared her many years of experience living in&amp;nbsp;Peru.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon, we explored Miraflores, one of Lima’s more affluent districts. It is heavily oriented toward tourism and also the neighborhood where our hostel was located. This was where I saw the Pacific Ocean for the first time—and, unfortunately, where I soaked my first and nicest of the four pairs of trousers I had brought with me in salty&amp;nbsp;seawater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also explored the area around the hostel: a small bar serving excellent pisco sours, several large green parks with free-roaming cats that you could pet (and, at least in theory, even adopt), and the multi-day coffee market known as &lt;em&gt;Semana del Café&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During these preparation days, our meals were organized by Ecoselva. We had lunch at an Arab restaurant and dinner at a Chinese one. The latter, unfortunately, didn’t convince most of us. Looking back, I’m sure we would handle it much better today. It was less a matter of taste than of adjustment—our bodies and expectations simply hadn’t arrived in Peru&amp;nbsp;yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding to this was the fact that I had suggested ordering an aloe vera drink, so that we could try everything that was on offer. That drink didn’t quite match our taste at the time, and the restaurant ended up with a rather mixed reputation within our group—probably also because everything felt so&amp;nbsp;unexpected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of the Pacific in Lima" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230536_DxO_HipNVxR4H.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of a metal pole with a sticker and the Pacific in the background" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230540_DxO_x4EQ_uVjc.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of a road and some buildings in Lima" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230556_DxO_Ldnar9w-0I.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="The Pacific behind a concrete bridge" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230559_DxO_uBmd7MWe1.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Waves of the Pacific hitting stones" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8230600_DxO_eGgQayloN.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Sunday, August 24,&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Far from the watchful eyes of security guards and the sweeping brooms of cleaning crews, we discovered a different side of Lima today: a city of around eleven million inhabitants, marked by stark social&amp;nbsp;contrasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We traveled to the district of Villa María del Triunfo, a so-called &lt;em&gt;pueblo joven&lt;/em&gt;—a structurally disadvantaged neighborhood, primarily inhabited by migrants from the Andes and often built through grassroots initiative. The journey itself was rough: in Peru, traffic laws are more of a suggestion, seatbelts are often decorative, and the horn is used far more frequently than the brake. For us newcomers from Germany, it initially felt chaotic, but it is simply part of everyday life&amp;nbsp;here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On site, we were introduced to a project focused on urban agriculture. Around fifteen years ago, a group of women decided to make their surroundings more livable. Since construction is prohibited beneath high-voltage power lines, they obtained permission to grow fruits and vegetables there instead. The beginnings were difficult, as few people believed in the project’s success. To get started at all, they built a makeshift fence out of tires, wooden planks, and corrugated metal to protect the gardens from&amp;nbsp;theft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, the project has expanded to several neighborhoods and includes many families cultivating small plots of land. Some sell their produce, while others grow food solely for their own consumption. What they all share is the care and dedication invested in their gardens. At lunchtime, we were invited to another project garden to enjoy a freshly prepared meal made from homegrown vegetables—an absolute&amp;nbsp;highlight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterward, we returned to the hostel, moving from the quiet, communal gardens back into the busy, noisy streets of Miraflores. There, I was able to fully enjoy the final day of &lt;em&gt;Semana del Café&lt;/em&gt;. Hidden between the warm aroma of coffee and the bustling crowd, I met several interesting people, including a tattoo artist who was creating temporary coffee-themed tattoos for visitors. Theo and I were welcome conversation partners, and we spent quite some time talking with him about his life and work in Peru—giving him a well-earned break from the market’s constant&amp;nbsp;activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later that evening, I also exchanged contact details with a few stallholders, from whom I bought sweaters, a waist bag, and a new pair of trousers. One thing became very clear during these days: when packing for the year ahead, I hadn’t always made the best&amp;nbsp;decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had carefully kept a packing list and eventually ended up with one that included everything I truly needed. But shortly before departure, I suddenly began negotiating that list with myself—using surprisingly poor arguments. Sweaters? I don’t need that many. Games? Who would I play with in a small village? Warm hiking clothes? I won’t be doing that in Peru. Well… I was very wrong and had to come up with creative stopgap&amp;nbsp;solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Triunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240631_DxO_xJ4J3gVrZ.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of a banana tree" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240629_DxO_tmrYuPpMN.jpg"&gt;&lt;p class="caption"&gt;The first time I had ever seen a banana&amp;nbsp;tree&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Triunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240636_DxO_pZkmJkSXxO.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Triunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240638_DxO_gi_7-5bmx.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Villa María del Triunfo" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8240642_DxO_xBG7qJlfa.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Monday, August 25,&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were supposed to meet a staff member from the German embassy today, who would provide us with further information about the country and our volunteer IDs. In Peru, many everyday processes require an identification number known as the &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. It is used for Yape—a digital payment method comparable to PayPal—as well as in hostels or for larger&amp;nbsp;purchases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meeting was canceled at short notice because the staff member fell ill. A blessing in disguise: with the extra time, we were able to buy &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SIM&lt;/span&gt; cards and finally reconnect with the outside world. We were now more independent and could move around the city more&amp;nbsp;freely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We took the bus to Lima’s historic center. Anyone who complains about overcrowded buses or subways in Germany wouldn’t even manage to get on a bus in Lima. They were so packed that you had to twist and squeeze more than in a game of Twister. Getting off the bus was an experience in itself, usually consisting of little more than the words “¡Bajo!” and&amp;nbsp;“Pásame.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The historic center itself impressed me deeply. Most of the buildings date back to the period of Spanish colonial rule, which began in 1535. Lima was founded as the “City of Kings” and long served as the seat of the Viceroy of Peru—one of the most important political and economic centers of the Spanish Empire in South America. The Church, the administration, and wealthy colonial elites invested in grand churches, imposing palaces, and richly decorated homes, using local materials such as brick, wood, and stone. All of this is clearly reflected in this &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UNESCO&lt;/span&gt; World Heritage&amp;nbsp;Site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ended the evening at Parque de la Reserva, where we watched an impressive fountain show while enjoying churros and fairground&amp;nbsp;attractions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;main class="carousel-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="carousel"&gt;
&lt;div class="item active"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250008_DxO_eZP13gl30.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250032_DxO_2TchPjv8a.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250045_DxO_mWZb9FTXF.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250052_DxO_1FiPlr7_e.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250099_DxO_y5kqsrqkm.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250124_DxO_6nd8-JWpU.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250154_DxO_XMbq0_BOW.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250172_DxO_qOFtIZhz_.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8250213_DxO_Pl9ZYhu-a.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260224_DxO_clMn0PQo6.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/721zjc9b0/images/P8260245_DxO_vUifIVnN9.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class="carousel-btn prev-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M15 18l-6-6 6-6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class="carousel-btn next-btn"&gt;&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 24 24"&gt;&lt;path d="M9 6l6 6-6 6" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-width="2"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;div class="modal" id="modal"&gt;&lt;span class="modal-close" id="modalClose"&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt="Full size image" class="modal-content" id="modalImage" src=""&gt;&lt;div class="modal-content" id="modalVideo"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;p align="right"&gt;Tuesday, August 26,&amp;nbsp;2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After another meeting with Doris, we visited the tourist district of Barranco today. We followed the coastal promenade and enjoyed the view of the Pacific, where I went swimming along with only a few others. Because of the cold, the swimmers later returned to the hostel by taxi. In the evening, we had empanadas—pastry pockets filled with cheese, chicken, or vegetables. For me, they were a good substitute for the kebab I wouldn’t be enjoying for the next&amp;nbsp;year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the final day, nothing else was planned, as everyone was leaving Lima at different times and Doris wanted to be present for all departures. In the afternoon, Erik and I met David, the head of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CACI&lt;/span&gt; Satinaki—the place where we would live and work. He explained many things to us, from the people there to travel opportunities during the&amp;nbsp;year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That same evening, we set off. Long-distance travel in Peru is largely done by bus, and the level of comfort is noticeably higher than in Germany. There are large terminals with luggage check-in, and the buses themselves are surprisingly comfortable: wide seats, plenty of legroom, and backrests that recline up to 160 or even 180 degrees. The eleven-hour journey to Pichanaki was therefore quite&amp;nbsp;enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happened there will follow in the next&amp;nbsp;post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back, those first days were overwhelming—but wonderful. Whether it was city life, the food, or the stark contrasts between different neighborhoods, I slowly realized that I had arrived in a culture unfamiliar to me, one in which I would spend an entire year. A year I’m genuinely looking forward to—for precisely that reason: cultural&amp;nbsp;exchange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stay tuned,
Buena semana y hasta la&amp;nbsp;próxima!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</ns0:content><ns0:category term="peru" /></ns0:entry></ns0:feed>